* * *

* Support
* Company

* Sign in

* Products
    
    * [TeamViewer Remote
        
        Connect to any device, at any time, and centrally monitor and manage your IT with the trusted remote access and support solution.
        
        Explore Remote](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/products/remote/)
    * [TeamViewer Tensor
        
        Scale, manage, secure support experiences across your enterprise efficiently with our remote connectivity platform.
        
        Explore Tensor](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/products/tensor/)
    * [TeamViewer Frontline
        
        Empower your frontline workforce and streamline shopfloor operations with our industrial augmented reality platform.
        
        Explore Frontline](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/products/frontline/)
    
    Learn more

* Solutions
    * By Industries
    * By Use Cases
    * By Roles
* Resources
* Partner

Privacy Notice
==============

1. General
2. TeamViewer US
3. Products
4. Cookie Notice
5. TeamViewer SE
6. Brazil (LGPD)
7. Data Protection Information

**General Privacy Notice by TeamViewer**
----------------------------------------

_Version as of March 21st, 2023_

TeamViewer Germany GmbH and its affiliates take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, such as name, address, email-addresses, IP address, or user behavior etc. The following document (“**General Privacy Notice**”) provides you with information about the processing of personal data in relation to administration of the contractual relationship between us as described and defined in the [End User License Agreement](https://www.teamviewer.com/eula/) (“**EULA**”) or any other agreements, as well as all other cases, when you may come in contact with us.

Further to this General Privacy Notice, please refer to our Product Privacy Notices for each of the respective products for detailed information concerning your use of the various TeamViewer products, such as TeamViewer Remote Access and Support, Frontline, IoT, Meeting (formerly blizz), Assist AR, Remote Management, Servicecamp, etc.

### A. Controller

TeamViewer Germany GmbH (“**TeamViewer**”), Bahnhofsplatz 2, 73033 Göppingen, Germany is controller pursuant to Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“**GDPR**”) concerning any processing of personal data for which we determine the purpose and means of processing.

### B. Data Protection Officer (DPO)

TeamViewer appointed an external data protection officer (DPO). In addition, TeamViewer established a dedicated Privacy team, which closely collaborates with the DPO. The Privacy team as well as the DPO can be reached at [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or at TeamViewer Germany GmbH, for the confidential attention of the DPO, Bahnhofsplatz 2, 73033 Göppingen, Germany.

### C. Categories of personal data, as well as purposes and legal basis for the processing

#### **C.1. When you visit our website(s)**

TeamViewer has to process certain personal data in order to be able to operate our website(s) and enable you barrier-free access to our content, as well as set certain cookies for the purposes of marketing and retargeting. We do this since we want to ensure that when you visit any parts of our website, your journey will be user-friendly, and especially that you do not encounter technical problems and malfunctions. Also, we would like to make sure we provide you with the most relevant content on our website, which may require that we consider certain personal data such as your browser’s language settings or the country from where you visit our services. In general, when you visit the TeamViewer website, we may collect IP address, date and time of the request, time zone, content of the request, data volume, browser information, your country of origin, as well as operating system as transmitted by your server to our servers.

The legal basis for processing this personal data is our legitimate interest, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR, or in some cases, your consent, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit a), Art. 49 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR.

Regarding personal data collected and processed in the context of web analytics and (re-)marketing activities as well as our use of Cookies, please refer to our [Cookie Notice](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/#cookie-notice).

#### **C.2. When you interact with us**

When you contact us (e.g., through an online contact form, through social media, email, chat functionality on our website or via phone), we will collect and process any personal information that you submit, such as your first name, last name, email-address, country, job title, phone number, company information (including company size), subject, description of your query etc. The collection of this data may be facilitated by third-party providers, which e.g., help us to provide particular landing pages or web forms or organize webinars (see Section D below). We will use the collected information for contacting you and serving your request, or to send you our advertising materials, depending on the type of the request and legal basis for the processing.

Depending on the individual case, we may process personal data based on your consent, to perform our contractual obligations under a contract or to follow our legitimate interest, or to fulfil a legal obligation to which we are subject to.

#### Learn more

##### **1\. When you contact us via website chat or by phone  
  
**

If you decide to reach out to us via our website chat or a phone, we may process your name, phone number, TeamViewer ID, inquiry type and any other information, that you may provide to us. If you reach us outside of business hours, we may store your message in order to get back to you as soon as possible. We need to process your personal data in order for us to properly respond to your request.

In some countries we utilize so called VoiceBot services, where the customer requests via phone are processed by our internal automated bot, which then automatically creates tickets in our system on your behalf.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data in this connection is your request prior to entering into a contract, or already existing contractual relationship, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._

Please note, that in some cases we may record phone calls between you and our employees for quality assurance and training purposes. Our employees may also be accompanied by specialized coaches and trainers that may listen in to such calls. We will notify you prior to any activity in this regard (e.g., before or during the call) and ask for your consent in accordance with Art. 6, para. 1 lit. a) GDPR, as well as inform you about other particularities of the processing.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is your consent, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR, which you may withdraw at any time with effect for the future._

##### **2\. When you submit a support ticket** 

If you submit a ticket regarding your TeamViewer product or any similar inquiry (e.g., updating your contact details, termination or renewal requests, commercial usage, technical issues, reverting the trial period, abuse of your license key etc.) using our online support ticketing system, we may process your name, email-address, TeamViewer ID, license key, invoice number, and any additional information you submit in connection with the ticket, depending on the request type. This may include your phone number, country, reason for submitting the ticket, log files compiling connection history, IP addresses, and information on your use of the TeamViewer product, but we will inform you separately in each case about the data that is required to resolve your request. At times, our employees may connect to your device remotely to help you resolve any issues that you may have.

We use our ticketing system to fulfil our business purpose to authenticate our product users and provide service resolution for our customers and free users.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is our contractual relationship with you, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._

##### **3\. When you request a quote or a demo from us** 

If you request a quote or a demo for one of our products, TeamViewer will collect and process any information you submit, such as your salutation, first name, last name, address, email-address, company, phone number, country, and product inquiry. We may also store some or all of that information in our customer relationship management system, which is facilitated by a third-party service provider (see Section D below). We require to process your personal data in this connection in order for us to properly respond to your request.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is your request prior to entering into a contract, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._

##### **4\. When you participate in a survey** 

If you participate in a survey performed by or on behalf of TeamViewer, we may collect and process your name, email-address, and user experience as well as any other personal information that you submit to us in the survey. Some surveys may be conducted on an anonymous basis, some however may be personalized. In each survey, we will inform you separately about additional personal data collected and processed. The participation in any of our surveys is of course, voluntary.  

If you participate in one of our surveys, we may process your personal data to analyze user experience and improve our product.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is your consent to participate in a survey, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit a) GDPR, which you may withdraw at any time with effect for the future._

##### **5\. When you participate in a sweepstake** 

We may, from time to time offer the participation in one of our sweepstakes. For this purpose, we will process your personal data as required for conducting the sweepstake, especially in order to select the winner in accordance with terms and conditions of the respective sweepstake. We will inform you about additional personal data collected and processed within the scope of each sweepstake, respectively.  

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is your agreement to participate in a sweepstake, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR, which you may withdraw at any time with effect for the future._

##### **6\. When you download one of our whitepapers** 

If you download one of our whitepapers, we may process your name, email-address, and other information as indicated in an individual form of the whitepaper download. If you show interest in our free whitepaper concerning our products, services or general technology updates, we will ask for your consent to subscribe you to our newsletter. You can unsubscribe from receiving such newsletters from us at any time by using the unsubscribe link included in each newsletter.  

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is your consent, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit a) GDPR, which you may withdraw at any time with effect for the future._

##### **7\. When you participate in one of our webinars** 

From time to time, we may offer our customers, users, and general public to attend our webinars relating to one of our products, modern technological advancements, or our collaborations with various partners. If you register to attend one of our webinars, we may process your name, job title, email-address, phone number, country, company, and other information, depending on the individual webinar. We will ask for your consent to subscribe you to our newsletter in connection with the webinar. You can unsubscribe from receiving such newsletters from us at any time by using the unsubscribe link included in each newsletter.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is our contractual obligation to allow you the participation in the webinar after the registration, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR, as well as your consent to receive the marketing communication from us. You can withdraw your consent at any time with effect for the future._

##### **8\. When you contact us on social media** 

If you visit any of our social media presence (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn, Xing) or leave us a comment or question, we may process your social media handle, your email-address, the content that you may interacted with (e.g., likes, shares, chat, documentation etc.) and any other personal information that you may leave on our respective page.

Please also refer to the respective privacy policies of relevant social media platforms:

* Facebook: [https://www.facebook.com/policy.php](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)
* LinkedIn: [https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)
* Instagram: [https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875](https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875)
* YouTube: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)
* Xing: [https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy)

We maintain the social media pages in order to keep in touch with our customers and free users worldwide, to share exiting news and updates about TeamViewer products and services and overall, provide up-to-date information to interested parties.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is our legitimate interest, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR._

##### **9\. When you request information on your personal data processed by us (data subject request)** 

If you submit a ticket requesting information on our processing of your personal data, we may process your email-address, TeamViewer ID as well as additional information in order to identify you in the first step, as well as, in case if we identify you, gather the personal data that we hold regarding you and provide you with it in a structured manner in accordance with the provisions of GDPR. Within the scope of answering your inquiry, we may process any kind of personal data as identified in our Product Privacy Policies. The processing purpose in this case is to answer your inquiry and to adhere to the legal obligation to which we are subject to.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is our legal obligation, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c) GDPR, as well as our legitimate interest, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR._

#### C.3. When you join our community

If you want to join TeamViewer’s [community](https://community.teamviewer.com/English), you will have to sign up and/or sign in with your TeamViewer credentials, such as your email-address, your name, and a password. After the signup, you will be able to interact with other members of the community, as well as our employees.

#### Learn more

In TeamViewer’s community, you may comment on different subjects concerning TeamViewer’s activities and products. In connection with your comments or posts in TeamViewer’s community, we may store your name/username (depending on your choice), email-address, IP address, content of your post and any additional information you submit. Further, we collect and process additional information on your comments, e.g., how many comments you post, how other members react to your comments or how valuable your comments are, in order to give certain rewards to TeamViewer community members. TeamViewer will, from time to time, respond to your comments to provide you with more information on any questions that you may have, e.g., provide you with technical solutions, legal information and like.

Your comment will be published in the relevant topic section by showing your username as the author. Please note that your comments are publicly accessible and will appear in search engines. Therefore, please consider carefully what you post prior to posting your comment. Further, we advise you to use an assumed name instead of your real name.

TeamViewer’s community helps us to satisfy our business purpose to assist product users with an open platform, on which issues, experiences and improvements can be shared and resolved. Your personal data is being processed so we understand what topics are most relevant to our users and for us to design our website user-friendly and interesting. TeamViewer also processes your personal data so that we are able to raise a defense in the event that a third party complains about your community comment’s content. In such case, TeamViewer needs to be able to contact you. Any comments you post may also be analyzed by TeamViewer against the community terms of use, including for the purpose of rewarding certain actions of community users.

_The legal basis for such processing is the user agreement concerning the use of our community and our legitimate interest of incentivizing positive contributions to the community as well as possible legal defense, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) in connection with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR._

#### C.4. When you enter into a contractual relationship with us

When you purchase a license for one of our products on behalf of your company, or use the Free Version of our Software, we may process certain personal data in order to conclude the agreement with you. In doing so, we may process your personal details, as well as the company details and payment information. We rely on the services of certified payment providers to process your payments and may conduct sanctions or fraud checks in accordance with applicable laws as well as to protect our business interests.

During the contractual relationship we may also process your personal data (e.g., your email-address, address, which products you have purchased etc.) in order to provide you with invoices, and other relevant contractual information.

Below you will find the applicable cases, where we may process personal data in connection with you purchasing the license.

#### Learn more

##### **1\. Processing the purchase**

When you purchase the license for your company through our webshop or our sales representative, we may process your salutation, your name, your title, company name, address, contact email-address, country, payment details, as well as other order details to provide you with purchased license and conclude an agreement as requested. We will also process information to support payment processing, including a payment token, which is provided by our payment service provider as a record of the transaction. When issuing our invoice, corresponding data such as an invoice ID, price paid, currency, invoice date, and tax code (e.g., VAT ID), will be collected and processed.

During each transaction, we may exchange your name, payment token, company information, payment method, contact information, and other relevant details with respective payment providers. Depending on customer’s location, different payment provider (Adyen or PPRO) may be used; Your data may also be shared with PayPal and your respective bank in order to process the payment. These details are relevant for the transaction to be completed. We only receive encrypted payment information back for the processing of new and recurring transactions, as well as from cancellation and refunds.

**Please note:** We do not process any clear payment details, such as your credit card numbers. We merely receive an encrypted piece of information in this connection. In case you do not terminate the agreement with us in accordance with termination provisions of the [EULA](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/eula/), we will request a recurring payment using the initial payment token or transaction ID to be executed by the relevant payment provider (e.g., through the same credit card or SEPA payment details last used by you). We will only store your payment details for SEPA direct debit mandate, if you (or your company) give us an explicit consent to do so.

Where you have purchased a license through one of our partners (resellers or distributors), they will transfer personal data they have collected in the context of your purchase to TeamViewer. We will use this data to process your purchase and for continuously providing our services to you.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR._

##### **2\. To manage and administer contractual relationship with you**

Once you have purchased a license, we will create a corresponding license key and add it, together with information on your license’s start and expiry dates to your TeamViewer account, which you will be asked to create (please see our Product Privacy Policies for any data collected and processed when creating a TeamViewer account). During the term of the contractual relationship, we may process some personal data in order to respond to your requests or inquiries, e.g., updating contact information, issuing/re-issuing invoices, sending payment reminders, creating credit notes, general customer communication, onboarding documentation etc. Data collected in the course of any purchase will be stored and further processed in our customer relationship management system, which is facilitated by a third-party service provider (see Section D below). After you place a purchase order, you will receive a link to activate Customer Portal, where you will be able to create an account with your email-address related to TeamViewer admin account. The Customer Portal is provided by TeamViewer in order to simplify license and contract management for you, respectively for your company. There you will find information about the current subscriptions, invoices, payments and other information related to overall license and contract administration.

We may also, from time to time contact you via email or our in-product messaging service to inform you about, i.a., upcoming changes in our [EULA](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/eula/), privacy policies, product updates, security updates. In doing so, we may process your name, email-address, product information (e.g., which TeamViewer version are you using) as well as your TeamViewer ID.

For the management of outstanding debt and unpaid invoices, TeamViewer utilizes the services of an external debt collection agency. For these purposes, TeamViewer may transfer your name, your company name, address, outstanding debt and other relevant contractual information to a debt collection agency. We currently cooperate with Creditreform Göppingen Engelhardt KG in this connection.

_The legal basis for all processing in this context is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR._

##### **3\. Contacting you in connection with your use of Free Version of the software**

If you use so-called Free Version of our software in accordance with the terms of our [EULA](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/eula/) for your personal and non-commercial purposes, we reserve the right to audit your use by technical means to assess whether your usage pattern is in line with the indicated usage volume and thus with the chosen license type (in this case, Free Version), and to detect whether the contractually agreed scope of use is being exceeded by you. Furthermore, we may require you, at any time, to provide a self-declaration regarding your actual scope of use and/or usage pattern.

To every extent possible, the described analyses will be based on pseudonymous data (e.g., we may consider your Device ID and data we have connected to your TeamViewer Device ID, rather than using immediately identifying personal data such as your name or email-address).

_We will process your personal data in this connection in order to make sure that our software is used in accordance with the EULA provisions and to exclude its misuse, therefore, the legal basis for processing this personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR._

##### **4\. To comply with our compliance obligations**

In order to abide with statutory compliance requirements, we conduct sanctions list checks for our customers, during which the following personal data may be processed: name, address, email address, phone number as well as respective tax ID. Personal data is checked against the sanctions lists provided by the German and European authorities.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is, therefore, Art. 6 para. 1 lit c) GDPR._

##### **5\. To conduct fraud and security checks**

In addition to sanctions list checks, we may conduct certain anti-fraud and security checks. The purpose is to exclude fraudulent activities and to protect ourselves as well as our other customers. In doing so, the following personal data may be processed: name, company name, company address, email address, phone number, IP address, device fingerprint, purchase details.

We utilize external tools which allow detecting any fraudulent activities with help of pre-configured rules and patterns. Purchases identified and confirmed as frauds will be stored in our system to prevent future fraudulent transactions.

The purpose of this processing is to check and ensure that no business relationship is established with fraudulent actors and companies and, if necessary, to terminate such relationships in time. TeamViewer has a legitimate interest in protecting its business and, its users and customers from fraudulent activities by bad actors.

_The legal basis of the processing this personal data is our legitimate interest, e.g., Art. 6, para.1 lit. f) GDPR._

#### C.5. When we reach out to you

We are of course interested in keeping in touch with our customers and users, as well as partners and suppliers, in order to keep you updated on relevant news, updates, contractual information, as well as to provide you with our marketing newsletters and information. In doing so, we may process your name, email-address, your TeamViewer ID and other contact information.

Below you will find detailed information on such cases, including on respective personal data processed and applicable legal basis.

#### Learn more

##### **1\. Contacting you through Social Media Channels**

We may, from time to time, contact you through various social media channels in order to inquire about your interest in our products and offerings. If you respond and /or show interest in our inquiry, we may process your name, your company information, your contact details as well as details around the service that you may be interested in.

We for example utilize the services of LinkedIn, in particular the Sales Navigator feature. For more information on LinkedIn Sales Navigator, please [refer to this link](https://business.linkedin.com/sales-solutions). Information on how LinkedIn processes your personal data can be found in their [privacy policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?).

_When we reach out to potential customers via multiple channels, the legal basis for doing so is our legitimate interest, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR connected later with the processing in order to enter into a contractual relationship with you, in case of your interest, hence i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._

##### **2\. Contacting you regarding our Status page**

If you subscribe to our [status page](https://status.teamviewer.com/), we will process your email address in order to notify you of any incidents, scheduled maintenances and operational statuses of our systems.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is your consent, e.g., Art. 6, para.1 a) GDPR which you may withdraw at any time with effect for the future._

##### **3\. Contacting you via email (newsletter) and in-product messaging**

If you sign up for our newsletter (marketing, product as well as our press releases), purchase a license for one of TeamViewer products, or use our free software version as a registered user, we may process your email-address for the purpose of sending you our newsletter. This also applies, when you sign up for a free webinar, download a free whitepaper, request or extend a product trial or participate in our sweepstakes.

Through our newsletters we want to provide you with information which is most relevant and interesting for you. For this reason, we (facilitated by our data processor Inxmail GmbH) may track reactions to and interactions with emails we send you (e.g., whether you open the newsletter, click on the text and image links or display the images contained in the emails).If you sign up for our newsletter, TeamViewer processes your personal data in order to send you the newsletter. If you have thus given us your consent, the legal basis for sending the newsletter to your email-address is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR. You may withdraw such consent at any time with effect for the future. Please use the unsubscribe link provided in each of the newsletter emails or contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

_If you have purchased a license, or use our software as a registered free user, we will subscribe you to our newsletter, which covers information about similar products to the one you purchased, on the basis of § 7 para. 3 of the German Unfair Competition Act (UWG) and Art. 6 para. 1 lit f) GDPR. In this case, you may object to receiving the newsletter at any time, and at no additional cost on our end by using the unsubscribe link provided in each of the newsletter emails or contacting [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)._

Tracking your and others’ reactions to and interactions with our newsletters helps us to deliver the content most useful for you, and to analyze and evaluate the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. We conduct such processing to fulfill our corresponding legitimate business interest pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit f) GDPR.

In addition to our email communication, we may from time to time contact you through our in-product messaging services to inform you about our new offers, discounts, and additional services that may interest you.

If you are a subscription user, you can disable the in-product messaging directly within your software. Alternatively, you can contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

#### C.6. When we analyze personal data

In certain cases, TeamViewer may combine and analyze certain information in the course of activities described in Sections C.2 to C.5 above together with the information available to TeamViewer internally, e.g., the use of the Software, respectively which Software have been purchased, or if a user recently started a trial of one of our products (incl. the information on your use of the product during the trial). TeamViewer conducts these analyses to decide on whether, when, and how to inform or get in touch with its customers and users. In this context, the aim is to convey relevant information about our products also in the most suitable manner, which may include in-product messages, email communications or contact by phone.

TeamViewer may also use the gathered information in order to prioritize the workload internally and to set up the processes more efficiently. Also, the analyses will assist in predicting as well as retrospectively evaluating the effectiveness of marketing and sales efforts, although such analysis and reporting is mostly done on an aggregated level.

To every extent possible, the described analyses measures will be based on pseudonymous data (e.g., we may consider the Google Analytics Client ID and other non-personalized cookie data, or data we have connected to your Device ID, rather than using immediately identifying personal data such as your name or email-address).

Furthermore, TeamViewer may analyze some personal data also in connection with the Free Version software as described in Section C.4.3.

_The legal basis for processing personal data for analysis purposes are performance of or processing prior to entering into a contract (e.g., when you contact our sales team and ask for a demo), i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b), Art. 49 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR, and/or our legitimate interest (e.g., when we try to find out what information about our products you might be most interested in and whether and how to best get in touch with you), i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR as long as no consent is required. For the data processing activities that require your consent, the processing is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a), Art. 49 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR._

#### Learn more

In this connection, TeamViewer may combine and conduct various analyses on the following data:

* the information you submit (e.g., when contacting our sales and support teams, requesting a quote or providing feedback) and, more generally, your interactions with our communication channels (e.g., metadata of phone calls, such as which personalized number you have called at what time, or email correspondence with our sales and support teams or your history of submitting tickets and how they have been handled);
* information on your interactions with our products (such as product usage data, or data on the types and frequency of connections you make) as described in our Product Privacy Policies;
* certain customer information, such as company name, job title, account information and purchase history (e.g., license information), as well as information whether you have started a trial, your participation in our webinars, and the like.

Based on the analysis and the results of it, TeamViewer then may:

* contact you by email, beyond sending our regular newsletter (e.g., to send out promotional materials to you as our customer or to invite you to participate in customer satisfaction and other surveys as described in Section C.2.4), using the email-address you submitted; or
* by phone using the phone number you submitted (e.g., during, or in due course after expiry of a product trial you requested or to follow up on feedback or inquiries you have placed with us); or
* conduct targeted advertising to inform you about changes to or improvements of our products, entirely new products, or to provide you with tips on how to best use our products as well as other useful information (e.g., on discounts, freebies or give-aways); we may do so on our websites, within our products and apps, or on third-party websites and apps.

#### C.7. When you are our partner, reseller or distributor

If you are one of our partners, reseller, or our distributor, we may process your name, your job title, your company, as well as contact details in order to manage the contractual relationship with you, respectively your company and to provide you with the newest information and updates about our offerings. Your personal data will be processed by our respective employees (e.g., Procurement, HR, IT etc.) throughout our cooperation. In this connection, we may also process your personal data through our so-called partner portal.

Furthermore, we may process and store your personal data in connection with our partner certification programs and your registration on and your use of our Partner Portal.

We require to process your personal data in order to maintain the contractual relationship between us.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR or our legitimate interest, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR._

#### C.8. When you are our supplier

If you are one of our suppliers, we may process your name, your job title, your company, as well as contact details in order to manage the relationship with you, respectively your company. Your personal data will be processed by our respective employees (e.g., Procurement, HR, IT etc.) throughout our cooperation.

We require processing your personal data in order to maintain the contractual relationship between us.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is, therefore, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR or our legitimate interest, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR._

#### C.9. When we receive your data from third parties

We may, from time to time, receive your personal data such as your name and your contact details from third parties, e.g., from event organizers, various trade fair organizers, partner websites, our integration partners (e.g., Salesforce, Microsoft, SAP etc.) and similar sources. The purpose of the transfer, as well as subsequent processing of personal data is, in most of the cases, marketing, and our desire to reach a wider audience with offers regarding our products and services. We always make sure that there is appropriate legal basis (e.g., your consent) in place, before even processing any personal data.

_The legal basis for processing this personal data is, therefore, either, your consent, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) or the contractual relationship with you, i.e., lit. b) GDPR. You may withdraw your consent at any time with effect for the future._

D. Recipients
-------------

Our employees, who administer, maintain and further develop TeamViewer’s website, Products and Services may receive access to your personal data. To that end, TeamViewer has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure to third parties and to ensure that only relevant individuals, who act within their job description and have a need-to-know interest in accessing any of your personal data, will have access to the data for which they have sufficient clearance.

In addition, we utilize services of external service providers (e.g., Microsoft, Amazon Web Services, Inxmail GmbH, Cloudfare etc.), as well as our affiliate network worldwide (e.g., TeamViewer entities in Greece, USA, Australia, Austria, Japan etc.).

All mentioned third-party providers and employees of such providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide.

TeamViewer chooses all third-party service providers with due care, obligates them to confidentiality, and concludes data processing agreements with them in accordance with the standards of the GDPR, as far as necessary. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

TeamViewer will generally not transfer your personal data outside the EU and/or EEA. However, there are some exceptions to this rule, which include data transfers for group internal services provided from outside the EU, including Australia, USA and Armenia as an example.

Whenever TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. In particular, we will conclude model contracts with corresponding entities in accordance with applicable laws. Please [refer to this link](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/standard-contractual-clauses-scc_en) to obtain further information on the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established outside the EU or EEA.

#### Learn more

* If you use our product, contact us through the contact, support, and feedback features, and/or if you request a quote, TeamViewer employees that are responsible for the respective service will receive access to your personal data. Aside from TeamViewer employees, your personal data may be processed by employees of third-party services providers, who assist us in handling your requests, e.g., if you use our chat functionality on the website, speak to us on the phone (e.g., external call centers), or contact us through forms on certain website landing pages (e.g., employees of the website support suppliers).
* If you post a comment in TeamViewer’s community or blog, your comment content and name/username will be publicly available and may appear in search engines. Aside from TeamViewer employees, employees of the hosting company may receive access to your personal data as described in Section C.3.
* If you purchase a TeamViewer Product, TeamViewer employees concerned with processing such transactions will receive access to your data. We also use the services of third-party payment token providers, such as PPRO Latin America GmbH and Adyen N.V. respectively. In addition, our fraud prevention software may also process your data on our behalf.
* In connection with hosting and processing your data on your behalf, we may use certain subprocessors, e.g., Anexia Internetdienstleistungs GmbH, Amazon Web Services, IBM Deutschland GmbH, Google Ireland Ltd., TeamViewer Austria GmbH, etc.
* TeamViewer may transfer your personal data to third parties if we offer participation in campaigns, contests, reservations, or contract agreements in conjunction with a third party. In this case, you will be specifically informed about the transmission to the third parties.
* For web analytics and (re-)marketing activities, we rely on a number of third-party providers, which will process personal data on our behalf as explained in more detail in our [Cookie Notice](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/#cookie-notice).
* Finally, TeamViewer uses external third-party service providers to help operate its business, such as providers of IT operation and maintenance services, (cloud) storage service providers and providers of (cloud) collaboration tools. Examples include Amazon Web Services and Microsoft (Dynamics 365, Azure).

As a global company, we may receive messages that require translation of the content of some inquiries. In such case, our employees use third-party translation tools in order to process your inquiry. Thus, you might want to avoid entering personal information into the subject line and description field of your inquiry.

E. Retention
------------

Your personal data will be deleted once you withdraw consent, or, more generally, once the purpose for processing of your personal data has ceased to exist. The exact retention period will thus depend on the categories of personal data and the processing purposes:

* Bookkeeping and accounting: In some cases, we are legally required to retain personal data for a certain period of time, e.g., for invoices, or payment details, for up to 10 years for these purposes.
* Marketing: for the data which we may process for marketing purposes, the retention period will depend either on your withdrawal of your consent, or if, in case the processing is based on our legitimate interest or the performance of a contract, the achievement of the processing purposes, e.g., two years for the pseudonymized usage data, or one year for a survey results.
* Protecting our legitimate interests: We may require storing personal data to protect our own legitimate interest, e.g., support ticket data or CRM data for up to 3 years (duration of statutory limitation period).

Once such period has lapsed, and there is no purpose to be fulfilled by the processing of personal data, we will delete or anonymize the data in accordance with data protection obligations.

F. Statutory/contractual requirement
------------------------------------

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data to us. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to engage in a contractual relationship with us or receive adequate support or may not be able to use all the functionalities of our website.

G. Your rights
--------------

You may contact us either in writing or by email at [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) in order to exercise the following rights to the extent you are entitled to under applicable law:

* You have the right to request information about the processing of your personal data in accordance with Art. 13 and 14 GDPR (Right to Information);
* You may request access to your personal data as well as request a copy of your personal data (Right of Access, Art. 15 GDPR);
* You may request that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data (Right to Rectification, Art. 16 GDPR and Right to Erasure, Art. 17 GDPR); the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
* You may request that we restrict the processing of your personal data (Right to Restriction of Processing, Art. 18 GDPR);
* You may request to receive your personal data, which you provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and transmit it without hindrance or have it transmitted to another controller (Right to Data Portability, Art. 20 GDPR);
* **You may object, at any time, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to the processing of your personal data which is based on the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. The processing of your personal data will then be cancelled, unless we demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights, and freedoms or the processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims (Right to Object, Art. 21 GDPR);**
* You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data.
* You have the right to opt out at any time from every processing activity which is based on your consent according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR. Your opt out does not affect the lawfulness of the processing in the past.

The relevant supervisory authority for TeamViewer is _Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Lautenschlagerstraße 20, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany_.

Should you have any questions on the processing of your personal data by TeamViewer Germany GmbH in relation to your contractual relationship, please contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

H. Compliance with the CCPA
---------------------------

Pursuant to the California Consumer Privacy Act (“**CCPA**”), you will not receive discriminatory treatment for exercising your privacy rights. You may also designate an authorized agent to make a privacy request on your behalf.

I. Compliance with Brazilian LGPD
---------------------------------

TeamViewer has checked the compliance topic with the Brazilian Data Protection Law Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados Pessoais (Law No. 13,709/2018) (“**LGPD**“) to ensure that our measures and procedures under the GDPR cover the topics within the LGPD. The privacy notice under the LGPD is available for Brazilian visitors and users under www.teamviewer.com/en-us/privacy-notice.

J. Changes to this Privacy Notice
---------------------------------

TeamViewer may, from time to time, make amendments to this Privacy Notice to reflect the changes in our processing activities.

**TeamViewer US Website Privacy Policy**
----------------------------------------

_Version as of March 2024_

### **YOUR PRIVACY: OVERVIEW**

If you are a located in North or South America, this privacy policy (“**Privacy Policy**“) explains how TeamViewer US, Inc. (collectively, “**TeamViewer**,” “**we**,” or “**us**“) collects, uses, discloses, and retains your personal data when you access or use our website. If you are located in India, then “TeamViewer,” “we,” and “us” refers to both TeamViewer US, Inc. and TeamViewer India Private Ltd., 5th floor, Spectrum Tower, Mindspace, Chincholi Bunder Road, Malad (West) Mumbai, MH, 400064. If you are located in Australia or New Zealand, then then “TeamViewer,” “we,” and “us” refers to both TeamViewer US, Inc. and TeamViewer Pty, Ltd., 118 Greenhill Road, SA 5061 Unley, Adelaide, Australia. Please review this Privacy Policy carefully.

Please note that the TeamViewer Group may provide different or additional privacy notices in connection with certain activities, products, services, and offerings. For more information about our privacy practices concerning our products, services, and other jurisdictions, please refer to the privacy policies posted on ours or the applicable TeamViewer Group website.

### **REVISIONS TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

TeamViewer reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will revise the date at the top of this Privacy Policy. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we may also choose to provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to our websites’ homepages or sending you a notification).

### **Content**

* [INFORMATION FOR CALIFORNIA CONSUMERS: YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS](#CA-privacy-rights)

### **COLLECTION OF PERSONAL DATA**

In this Privacy Policy, “personal data” means any information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with or reasonably can be used to identify an individual or household and other data that is linked to personal data. The types of personal data we collect about you depend on your interactions with us and are described in more detail below.

### PERSONAL DATA YOU PROVIDE DIRECTLY TO US THROUGH THE USE OF THE WEBSITE

We collect personal data directly from you in a variety of ways, including when you:

* Fill out lead forms;
* Request additional information about our products or services or sign up to receive our e-mail newsletters or marketing messages;
* Interact with us on social media;
* Participate in or respond to surveys or requests for opinions, feedback and preferences;
* Contact us through an online contact form, chat function on our website, or via phone;
* Subscribe and/or post to our blog;
* Provide feedback or make other submissions to us; and
* Participate in a survey performed by or on behalf of TeamViewer.

The types of data we collect directly from you may include: your first name, last name, e-mail address, address, telephone number, country, job title, phone number, username, company information (including company size), demographic information, personal preferences, reactions to and interactions with our communication channels, account information, purchase history, and any other personal data that you choose to include in your submissions or communications with us.

### PERSONAL DATA AND DATA WE COLLECT AUTOMATICALLY

We automatically collect personal data when you access and use our website. The types of information we collect may include:

* Networking and device information, such as your browser type, IP address, and operating system version, language settings;
* Information about your website activities, such your access times, pages viewed, the routes by which you came to our website, your use of any hyperlinks available within our services; and
* Information collected via cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies, including Internet service provider (ISP), Mobile Advertising ID, media access control (MAC) address, or identifiers associated with browser cookies, web beacons and similar technologies we deploy on our services.

### PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT FROM OTHER SOURCES

We may collect personal data about you from other sources. For example, we may collect personal data about you from:

* Third parties hosting events, including those sponsored by TeamViewer, when they share event attendance or participation information with us;
* Third-party social media and communication services, such as Facebook, Twitter, Google, LinkedIn, and Instagram, that you use to interact with our services (e.g., to create an account) or that allow you to share information (e.g., via plugins, widgets or other tools), but always in accordance with the authorization procedures and privacy settings you establish with such services; and
* Unaffiliated parties, such as service providers that we use, analytics companies, advertising networks, consumer data resellers, and other third parties that provide us with information, so we can better understand you and provide you with information and offers that may be of interest to you.

### PERSONAL DATA WE DERIVE

We may derive information or draw inferences about you based on the other types of personal data we collect. For example, we may infer your location based on your IP address.

### **USE OF PERSONAL DATA**

We collect and use personal data for business and commercial purposes, including to:

* Develop, provide and improve our events and websites;
* Respond to your requests and any other communications from you;
* Send advertising or marketing communications about products, services, offers, promotions, rewards and events offered by TeamViewer and others, and provide news and information that we believe may be of interest to you;
* Offer and administer events, contests, and other promotions;
* Conduct internal research and development;
* Comply with our legal obligations; and
* Debug, identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality of our website.

### **DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL DATA**

We share personal data for the purposes described below:

a. With our Affiliates and Subsidiaries. Disclosures of your personal data to the TeamViewer Group, including our parent entities, subsidiaries and affiliates (as the case may be), for the purposes described in the “USE OF PERSONAL DATA” section above. Specifically, if and when you become a TeamViewer customer we may share information such as your name, email address, address, telephone number, country, job title, username, company information (including company size), demographic information, personal preferences, reactions to and interactions with our communication channels, account information, purchase history, chosen payment method, information to support payment processing (including a payment token), invoice ID, price paid, currency, invoice date, tax code, license key, license start and expiry dates, and any other information collected through our websites or that you choose to include in your profile or in other communications with us. Since our parent company, subsidiaries and affiliates are located around the world, please note that these disclosures involve international transfers of your personal data.

b. With our Service Providers. We share personal data with unaffiliated companies or individuals we hire or work with that perform services on our behalf, including customer support, web hosting, information technology, payment processing, product fulfilment, fraud control, direct mail and email distribution, events, contests, sweepstakes and promotion administration, and analytics services. We only share with service providers the personal data that they need to perform services for us. Since our service providers are located around the world, please note that these disclosures involve international transfers of your personal data.

c. With our Professional Advisors. We share personal data with our legal, financial, and other advisors in connection with the management of all or part of TeamViewer’s business or operations.

d. With Law Enforcement Authorities and Individuals Involved in Legal Proceedings. We disclose personal data when we believe doing so is reasonably necessary to comply with applicable law or legal process (including an enforceable request from authorities), to respond to claims (including inquiries by you in connection with your purchases from TeamViewer), or to protect the rights, property or personal safety of TeamViewer, our users, employees or the public.

e. With Your Consent or at Your Direction. We share personal data with third parties when we have your consent to do so. For example, if you decide to participate in certain interactive areas or features of our events or services, you consent to the disclosure of this information to other users of our websites. We may also share your personal data with third parties when you intentionally direct us to do so or when you use our services to intentionally interact with third parties.

We may also share aggregated or de-identified information, which cannot reasonably be used to identify you.

### **ADVERTISING AND ANALYTICS SERVICES PROVIDED BY OTHERS**

We may allow others to provide analytics services and serve advertisements on our behalf across the web and in mobile applications. These entities may use cookies, web beacons, device identifiers, and other tracking technologies which collect information about your use of our services and other websites and applications. This information may be used by TeamViewer and others to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interest on our services and other websites, and better understand your online activity.

Such tools include:

### 1\. Google Analytics and Other Analysis Tools Provided by Google

TeamViewer uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, or any other Affiliate of Google LLC (“**Google**“). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, i.e. text files that are stored on your computer and enable analysis of your use of our website. When you visit our website for the first time, you will be assigned a cookie with a unique user identification, i.e. a **Google Analytics Client ID**. We may replace this Google Analytics Client ID with your TeamViewer Device ID if you use one of our products (please refer to our [Product Privacy Policy](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/#products) for details). We will add the respective data point to the data available in the Google Analytics tools, and this way we use Google Analytics also for cross-device analyses of user streams.

Other tools we use in this context that are also provided by Google include:

* **Google Tag Manager** (a tag management system that allows TeamViewer to quickly and easily update tracking codes and related code fragments collectively known as “tags” on our website or mobile app);
* **Google Big Query** (an enterprise data warehouse that enables SQL queries using the processing power of Google’s infrastructure; TeamViewer uses Big Query to store and query data sets which are collected by Google services such as Google Analytics, and the Big Query data is used to build flexible reports for evaluating our website performance);
* **Google Display Network** (used to measure the impact of unclicked Google Display Network ad impressions on the website, behavior of users, and conversions; please refer to [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/3105620](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/3105620) for further information); and
* **Google Optimize** (for A/B testing, offering to analyze user behavior by showing slightly varied website contents to different user groups, depending on profile matching; thereby, TeamViewer analyzes its online services, improves its web offerings, and can create an interesting user journey).

TeamViewer Group uses data gathered through your Google Analytics Client ID as well as other data generated from Google’s web analytics applications in order to perform analyses of your interactions with our products, services, and websites. With the help of Google’s Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, we will receive analyses on our users’ age, gender, and interest categories (please refer to [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en) for further information). We strive to offer you tailored products and services that are best suited for your individual circumstances. To that end, Google provides us with insights and statistics that help us to make our online presence, our communications to you, and ultimately our products more interesting and relevant for you.

As further explained in our [Cookies Policy](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/#cookie-notice), you may block cookies from being stored on your device, and consequently prevent the described analyses from being conducted, by adjusting the settings in your browser software; however, in such case, you may not be able to use all of the features and functionalities of our website. You can also block the collection of the data generated by the cookie and the data related to your use of the website (incl. your IP address) as well as the processing of this data by Google, by downloading and installing a browser plugin available from the following link: [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

Please visit the website [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en) for an overview on Google’s approach on data protection for Google Analytics as well as their privacy policy: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

### 2\. Demandbase

TeamViewer uses web analytics services provided by Demandbase Inc., located at 680 Folsom Street, Suite 400 San Francisco, CA 94107 USA. Demandbase utilizes tracking technology, which includes the storing and accessing of cookies, to collect data about website visitors. Demandbase’s Tags, or JavaScript, pixels, cookies or other similar technology or code, cause a unique cookie ID to be associated with each visitor who accesses our website and may sync with third-party cookies. Demandbase’s Tags on our website may collect data on device information (such as a website visitor’s IP address), cookies, or other technical information (such as web browser type, operating system or timestamp).

The Demandbase Tags are used for analytics and advertising services provided by Demandbase. They are also used for performance and optimization of Demandbase data and reporting. Demandbase’s services help us tailor our communications and improve the quality of the content we provide to our prospects, users, and customers. It also helps to improve our website user experience and performance by personalizing and optimizing the website for visitors.

For further information on Demandbase’s privacy approach, visit [https://www.demandbase.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.demandbase.com/privacy-policy/). For more details on the cookies used by Demandbase, visit [https://www.demandbase.com/cookies/](https://www.demandbase.com/cookies/).

### 3\. Google AdWords Conversion and Google Remarketing

TeamViewer’s website uses Google AdWords in order to generate attention for our products and services by conducting targeted advertising campaigns on third-party websites and apps. Data generated by such campaigns helps us to determine the success rate of individual campaigns. TeamViewer aims at providing you with advertisement that is of interest to you, to make its website more interesting, and calculate advertising expenses accurately.

Such means of advertisement are delivered by Google through a so-called Ad Server. Along with this, TeamViewer uses **Ad Server Cookies**, which scale certain parameters, such as display of ads or clicks by users. When you click on an ad delivered by Google that redirects you to our website, a cookie is stored on your computer by Google AdWords. These cookies usually expire within 30 days and are not supposed to be used to personally identify a user. In addition to these cookies, analytic values like a **unique cookie ID, quantity of Ad impressions per storing, last impression and opt-out information** (markings that the user does not want to be addressed any further) are usually stored. These cookies enable Google to recognize your internet browser.

If you visit certain pages on our website and provided the cookie stored on your computer has not yet expired, TeamViewer and Google are able to recognize that you clicked on an ad and were redirected to the TeamViewer website. Every Google AdWords customer receives a different cookie. Therefore, cookies cannot be tracked across different sites by TeamViewer, as is the case for all other AdWords customers. TeamViewer merely receives statistical evaluations from Google. By and through these statistical evaluations, we can evaluate which advertisement campaign was particularly effective. Any additional data generated by the particular advertisement is not forwarded to TeamViewer; particularly, we cannot personally identify users through this information.

Through this (re-)marketing tool, your browser automatically connects to Google’s servers. Please note that scope and further use of the data processed by Google are subject to Google’s privacy policy and beyond TeamViewer’s control. We thus inform you based on our own knowledge: By integrating AdWords, Google receives information that you visited a particular TeamViewer website or part thereof, and/or that you clicked on one of our advertisements. If you are registered with one of Google’s services, Google is able to match your visit to your Google account. Google may receive your IP address and/or may store it even if you are not registered with one of Google’s services and/or if you have not been logged in. You may avoid tracking in various ways, e.g. through:

* a setting of your browser software, particularly, by suppressing third party cookie installation in order to prevent receiving third-party ads;
* deactivating AdWords Cookies, by setting your browser so that cookies from www.googleadservices.com are being blocked; this can be done at [https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous](https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous), however, such settings are deleted if you delete cookies; or
* permanently deactivating cookies in your browser under [https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996).

Further information on Google’s approach to data privacy can be found under [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). Alternatively, you can disable the use of cookies for interest-based advertising via the advertising network initiative, by following the instructions at [https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!%2F](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!%2F).

In addition to Google AdWords, TeamViewer uses the tool “**Google Remarketing**.” This is an application that allows us to address you again, even when you have left our website. After visiting our website and while you are surfing the internet, our advertisement can be displayed to you by and through this application. This is enabled by cookies stored on your device, which track and analyze user behavior on different websites for Google. Google can track your previous visits to our website.

According to its own statement, Google does not combine data gathered through Remarketing with any personal data Google may have stored about you. Furthermore, the data processed for these purposes is generally limited to pseudonymous information. If you do not want to be exposed to data processing through the Google Remarketing feature, you can disable it by changing the appropriate settings at [https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous](https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous).

### 4\. Social Media Tracking Tools, including “Tracking Pixels”

We also use other tools on our website allowing us to offer you a more personalized and engaged web experience by offering you advertisements on your social media channels that are more relevant to you. To that end, we use cookie-based (please refer again to our [Cookies Policy](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/#cookie-notice)) tools offered by the following third-party social media providers:

* **Facebook Inc.**, 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA; for further information on the implemented tool, please refer to [https://developers.facebook.com/docs/facebook-pixel/implementation#base-code](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/facebook-pixel/implementation#base-code); for additional information on data collection, refer to [https://www.facebook.com/help/186325668085084](https://www.facebook.com/help/186325668085084).
* **LinkedIn Corporation**, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, California 94043, USA; for further information on the implemented tool and how to opt out of corresponding tracking, please refer to [https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out); for further information on LinkedIn’s approach to privacy refer to: [https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=uno-reg-guest-home-privacy-policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=uno-reg-guest-home-privacy-policy).
* **Twitter Inc.**, 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, California 94103, USA; for further information on the implemented tool and how to opt out of corresponding tracking, please refer to [https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads](https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads); for further information on Twitter’s approach to privacy refer to: [https://twitter.com/en/privacy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy).

In each case, we integrate snippets of code provided by these social media operators that load a small library of functions (sometimes referred to as “tracking pixels”, i.e. transparent, pixel-sized images embedded in websites with a tracking functionality). These functions enable us to track your activities on our website, such as URLs visited, domains visited, device(s) used, and, in particular advertising conversions (i.e. actions counted when you interact with one of our ads, such as clicking it and purchasing our product afterwards). They rely on cookies placed by the mentioned third-party providers, which may also enable us to match our website visitors to respective user accounts on the respective social media platforms.

We may also use the “**Custom Audience**” service provided by Facebook Inc., for delivering targeted advertising to you. In this context, we would check whether you hold an account with Facebook for which you use the same email-address that you have provided to us and include you in a corresponding “custom audience” group. This works by us providing your email-address to Facebook Inc. in a hashed format, and this way making sure that Facebook will only process, as a data processor on our behalf, actual email-addresses of users that have already subscribed to their service (please refer to [https://www.facebook.com/business/help/112061095610075?id=2469097953376494&helpref=faq\_content](https://www.facebook.com/business/help/112061095610075?id=2469097953376494&helpref=faq_content) for further information on this process). You may opt-out of receiving targeted ads because you are part of a custom audience created by TeamViewer through clicking a corresponding link when you select the “Why am I seeing this?” feature on the Facebook platform (see [https://www.facebook.com/help/562973647153813?helpref=about\_content](https://www.facebook.com/help/562973647153813?helpref=about_content)).

Like many websites, TeamViewer uses “cookies” to analyze visits to our website and help us improve our website and services. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually set your browser to remove or reject cookies. Please follow your browser’s process for doing so. Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our websites. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purpose for which we use them, see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/#cookie-notice).

### **RETENTION OF PERSONAL DATA**

Your personal data will be deleted once you withdraw consent, or, more generally, once the purpose for processing has ceased to exist. In some cases, TeamViewer is legally obligated to retain data for a certain period. Once this period has lapsed, TeamViewer will delete the data in accordance with data protection obligations.

### **CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

TeamViewer’s services are not intended for children under the age of 18. TeamViewer does not target our services to children under 18.

### **THIRD PARTY SITES**

Please note that our websites contain links to third-party websites that are not controlled or operated by TeamViewer. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that TeamViewer does not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please review these policies before you disclose any personal data when visiting such third-party websites.

### **SECURITY PRACTICES**

We take the safety of your personal data and its confidentiality very seriously and we provide reasonable security safeguards commensurate to the sensitivity of the personal data being handled and have implemented security practices including but not limited to technical, operational, and physical safeguards to protect your information. We implement a variety of security measures when entering, submitting, or accessing information to maintain the safety of your personal data. The website is scanned on a regular basis for any known vulnerabilities in order to make your use as safe as possible.

Your personal data is contained behind secured networks and it only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems or otherwise require personal data for appropriate purposes. These persons are also under an obligation to keep such personal data confidential. All of the data centers TeamViewer uses have achieved ISO/IEC 27001 certification, which is the international standard for information security management systems and security controls. The data centers have implemented state-of-the-art security controls, which means that personal access control, video camera surveillance, motion detectors, 24×7 monitoring, and on-site security personnel ensure access to the data center is only granted to authorized persons and guarantee the best possible security for hardware and data. There is also a detailed identification check at the single point-of-entry to the data center.

Please be aware that, although we endeavor to provide reasonable security for your personal data, no security system can prevent all potential security breaches.

We endeavor to ensure that all third-party service providers whose services which we may use, maintain security standards that are equivalent to our security standards and commensurate with market practices, in the context of the kind and nature of personal data being stored or handled.

For more information, you may visit the [TeamViewer Trust Center](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/trust-center/) or request for a copy of our Security Measures.

### **YOUR RIGHTS**

You may contact us in order to exercise the following rights to the extent you are entitled to so under applicable law:

* You may access your personal data to check and review such data;
* You may request a copy of your personal data;
* You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; and
* You may withdraw consent and/or object to the processing of your personal data; and
* You may request to receive your personal data in a portable and (if technically feasible) readily usable format.

To submit such a request, please contact us under [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), at 1-800-638-0253, or [submit a ticket](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/global/support/customer-support/) on our website. Your request will be promptly attended to by a member of our team. TeamViewer may request your name, email address, and/or account information in order to verify your request.

Should you have any questions, please contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

This Privacy Policy contains links to sites and information that are not under TeamViewer’s direct control. These links are therefore subject to change and TeamViewer will review and update this Privacy Policy periodically to reflect such changes.

### **INFORMATION FOR CALIFORNIA CONSUMERS: YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

#### ADDITIONAL DISCLOSURES RELATED TO COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL DATA

The California Consumer Privacy Act (“**CCPA**”) allows California residents, upon a verifiable consumer request and subject to applicable exemptions, to request that we give you access, in a portable and (if technically feasible) readily usable form, to the specific pieces and categories of personal information that we have collected about you, the categories of sources for that information, the business or commercial purposes for collecting the information, and the categories of third parties with which the information was shared. California residents also have the right to submit a request for deletion of information under certain circumstances.

Consistent with California law, TeamViewer will not discriminate against those who exercise their rights. Specifically, if you exercise your rights, we will not deny you services, charge you different prices for services or provide you a different level or quality of services.

To submit a data request, please contact us under [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), at 1-800-638-0253, or [submit a ticket](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/global/support/customer-support/) on our website. Please note that you must verify your identity and request before further action is taken. Consistent with California law, you may designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf. In order to designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf, you may have to provide a valid power of attorney, the requester’s valid government issued identification, and the authorized agent’s valid government issued identification.

We collect personal data from you and the sources described in the “[PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT FROM OTHER SOURCES](#collection-personal-data)” subsection of this Privacy Policy.

In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have collected the following categories of personal data: identifiers, characteristics of protected classifications under California or U.S. law, commercial information, internet and electronic network activity, geolocation data, audio and visual information, inferences drawn about your preferences, and other categories of personal data that relates to or is reasonably capable of being associated with you. For examples of the precise data points we collect, see the section titled “[COLLECTION OF PERSONAL DATA](#collection-personal-data)” in this Privacy Policy.

We do not sell personal information to third parties, as that is defined under the CCPA.

In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have shared personal information with third parties for business purposes as further detailed in this Privacy Policy. We may share your personal data with third parties as described in the “[DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL DATA](#disclosure-personal-data)” section of this Privacy Policy.

In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have disclosed the following categories of personal data for business or commercial purposes: identifiers, internet and electronic network activity information, commercial information, audio and visual information, geolocation data, demographic information, inferred information, and other information that we have derived or inferred about you or that relates to or is reasonably capable of being associated with you. For information on the business or commercial purpose for using the personal data, see the section of this Privacy Policy titled “[USE OF PERSONAL DATA](#use-personal-data).”

### **CONTACT US**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, you may contact us at 1-800-638-0253 or [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

### **IMPRINT**

TeamViewer US, Inc.  
5741 Rio Vista Drive  
Clearwater, FL 33760  
USA

### **TEAMVIEWER GROUP PROCESSING**

We share also collect, use, and share data and personal data with other entities within the TeamViewer Group as it relates to a number of functions and activities related to the TeamViewer products, which are developed by, maintained, and contracted with our parent company, TeamViewer Germany GmbH. Examples of this include, but are not limited to, purchasing a product or service, concluding a purchase transaction, product trials, customer support, participation in customer online forums, and other customer-related activities. For more information for how we process this data and personal data, please visit our [TeamViewer Group Privacy Policy](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/).

**Privacy Notice for TeamViewer Products**
------------------------------------------

_Version as of May 7th, 2024_

TeamViewer Germany GmbH and its affiliates take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, such as name, address, email-addresses, IP address, or user behavior etc. The following document (“**Privacy Notice**”) provides you with information about the processing of personal data in relation to your use of our Software and Services as described and defined in the [End User License Agreement](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/eula/) (“**EULA**”) in connection with the use of our Software and Services (hereinafter, “**Products**”).

Depending on the processing activity and its purpose, TeamViewer may act as either (i) a controller as defined by the General Data Protection Regulation (“**GDPR**”), or (ii) as a processor as defined in more detail in our [EULA](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/eula/) and our [Data Processing Agreement](https://www.teamviewer.com/eula/#dpa) (“**DPA**”).

Subsequently, TeamViewer may process the various personal data for various purposes and in a different capacity.

#### Learn more

On a case-by-case basis, TeamViewer may act in a different capacity in accordance with applicable laws and regulations. Concrete examples of which personal data we process in which capacity are as follows:

* Personal data in connection with our agreement with you, e.g., your contact information. More information on this and how we process personal data as controllers for maintaining our contractual relationship with our users and customers can be found in our [General Privacy Notice](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/privacy-and-cookies/).
* Personal data in connection with your account (e.g., your email, password, username etc.), as well as with various TeamViewer Features, esp. initiating connections, hosting of your contact lists, or managing a team of people using our Product under your license. In this context TeamViewer may act as processors as defined under Art. 4 no. 8 GDPR. More on processing in this context can be found in our [DPA](https://www.teamviewer.com/eula/#dpa), respectively in its [Annexes](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/dpa-annex/).
* Personal data derived from your use of our Products and Services, e.g., your feedback, as well as statistical and analytical data for marketing and product development purposes. In this case TeamViewer may act as controller of such data. This Privacy Notice serves the purpose to provide more information in this context.

Below you will find more information on when, how, and why we process your personal data in connection with your use of our Products.

A. Controller
-------------

TeamViewer Germany GmbH (“**TeamViewer**”), Bahnhofsplatz 2, 73033 Göppingen, Germany is controller pursuant to Art. 4 para. 7 GDPR concerning any processing of personal data for which we determine the purpose and means of processing.

B. Data Protection Officer (DPO)
--------------------------------

TeamViewer appointed an external data protection officer (DPO). In addition, TeamViewer established a dedicated Privacy team, which closely collaborates with the DPO. The Privacy team as well as the DPO can be reached at [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or at TeamViewer Germany GmbH, for the confidential attention of the DPO, Bahnhofsplatz 2, 73033 Göppingen, Germany.

C. Categories of personal data, purposes, and legal basis for the processing
----------------------------------------------------------------------------

#### C.1. When you use TeamViewer Products  

##### C.1.1. Getting started  

When you install the Software and use the Product for the first time on a new device, we need to collect certain information from that device, such as your IP address, device’s MAC address, operating system (OS) specific identifier combined with other device-related information to ensure its uniqueness. From this information, TeamViewer creates a unique Machine ID (MID), from which the TeamViewer master infrastructure generates the TeamViewer Device ID, which in turn allows it to distinguish between unique user devices that have the Software installed.

When you sign up for a TeamViewer account, TeamViewer collects your name, email-address, a password of your choice, along with time, date, and time zone of you signing in and creates a unique TeamViewer Account ID for your TeamViewer account.

Should you choose to add the additional security option of two factor authentication to your account, TeamViewer will process the data required to provide this option and to maintain your accounts security including: Number of login attempts, location and whether the session is active, Mobile phone number, TeamViewer ID.

TeamViewer requires the Edge WebView2 Runtime by Microsoft for the user interface. If not already installed, it will be downloaded and installed when you click ‘Accept – next’. The Edge WebView2 Runtime may collect information and send it to Microsoft to provide services as described in Microsoft’s Privacy Statement at [https://aka.ms/privacy](https://aka.ms/privacy).

#### Learn more

During the installation, we will also ask you whether (i) you would like to explore the full-featured business trial, (ii) if you wish to only use the Product for personal use, or, (iii) if you already have a license. According to your choice, you may be directed to our license trial page, or you may continue with software installation process. During so, if you decide to sign up for a TeamViewer account, we will collect your name, email-address, a password of your choice, along with time, date, and time zone of you signing in and create a unique TeamViewer Account ID for your TeamViewer account.

In some countries we may ask our users to provide their phone numbers for identification purposes. This may be done for the purposes of strengthening our security and ensuring proper authentication.

Furthermore, TeamViewer may process your personal data for the purposes of license management. When a customer activates the license with help of the license sync option, TeamViewer license server checks the information to assign the license to the correct customer. In doing so, some personal data may be processed, such as license information (e.g., license ID, roles and permissions, type), system information (e.g., license key, server configuration), user information (e.g., email, IP address, status, language, organization) or session information (ID, security tokens, IP address, username device, etc.).

TeamViewer is processing personal data in connection with license management in order to assign you the required license, and, consequently, for the performance of the contract with you.

_The legal basis to process your personal data as described under this Section, is performance of our contract with you (i.e., the EULA) and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._ 

##### C.1.2. Social Login Services  

You also have the option to create or log in into a TeamViewer account via an identity provider, e.g., Microsoft Ireland Operations Ltd. (One Microsoft Place, South County Business Park, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, Ireland), Google Ireland Ltd. (Gorden House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, etc.). This makes it easier for you to register for our products. Through this, we offer you the possibility to register or log in into a TeamViewer account via an identity provider to use our products.

If you use an identity provider, you will be forwarded to the identity provider’s page. There you can create an account or log in with an already existing account via your user data. The identity provider will ask for your consent to release certain information about your account to us. This data is collected by the Identity Provider and transmitted to us by the Identity Provider in compliance with the relevant provisions of the privacy notice. TeamViewer receives an identification token from the identity provider that contains information used to create, or connect to, your account (username and e-mail-address). TeamViewer will process the email address and username received from this identity provider for registration and login to your account. To carry out this authentication process, your IP address is transmitted to the respective identity provider. We have no influence on the purpose and scope of the data collection and on the further processing of the data by the identity provider. For more information, please read the privacy policy of the respective provider. By using the login via an identity provider, you agree to this data transfer to us. TeamViewer will also directly collect from you some of the information needed for providing the account (as described above, C.1.1.). You can prevent the processing of your data by the respective identity provider by not using the identity provider but using our own registration form and signing up for a TeamViewer account.

_The legal basis for the processing of your personal data in connection with an identity provider is your consent pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a), 7 GDPR._ 

##### C.1.3. Conducting remote connections  

Whenever you run the TeamViewer Software client, the TeamViewer master server infrastructure will register whether the device is available for a connection session with other devices. To achieve that, it collects and processes your IP address, your location, TeamViewer Device ID, the Machine ID, and your chosen user screen name. While trying to connect to another device, this data is exchanged between the TeamViewer master server infrastructure, selected TeamViewer routers, and the Software client of your envisaged connection partner. In addition, our servers will automatically collect certain remote connection metadata (so called logs, which can later be used to address and analyze technical bugs and difficulties).

#### Learn more

The decision on which connection paths are used, in particular which routing servers, depends on the analysis of this data, considering e.g., geography and current workload on individual routers. Once you successfully connect to another device and thus establish a remote control or other session with your connection partner, certain session metadata such as a remote connection (session) ID will be collected and processed.

_The legal basis to process your personal data as described under this Section, is performance of our contract with you (i.e., the EULA) and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._

##### C.1.4. Using Text recognition feature (Frontline and Assist AR)  

Functionalities of Frontline and Assist AR include, amongst others, a text recognition feature. It is based on the use of a text recognition API provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, California 94043, United States (“Google”), that also enables the activation of the Optical Character Recognition (OCR) functionality on smart glasses used with Frontline and Assist AR. If technically possible, the API contacts Google servers from time to time in order to receive things like bug fixes, updated models and hardware accelerator compatibility information. It may also send telemetry data about the performance and utilization of the API in the Assist AR App to Google. Such data include device information, application information, device or other identifiers, performance metrics, API configuration, event type and error codes (you can find further information here). Google uses this data to measure performance, debug, maintain and improve the API, and detect misuse or abuse, as further described in Google’s Privacy Policy. Before you may use this feature, we ask for your consent to the described data processing.

_The legal basis to process this personal data as described under this Section, is your consent and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR._ 

##### C.1.5. Adding devices to your account  

When you add so called managed devices to your TeamViewer account, we activate these devices as endpoints that are assigned to your license. To achieve that, TeamViewer collects, and processes certain data associated with those managed devices, e.g., screen name, TeamViewer ID, Machine ID, email address, account ID, License ID and, if mobile device management is purchased: location data, and mobile device data. During the activation of an endpoint TeamViewer needs to ensure that the Product is used in accordance with the EULA and Product Specifications.

This is done to assign and enforce the license limits as agreed with you under your contract.

_The legal basis to process your personal data as described under this Section, is performance of our contract with you (i.e., the EULA) and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._ 

##### C.1.6. Using the Backup feature  

If you choose to use our optional feature Backup, we may process the information on your purchased storage limits in order to assign you the relevant storage space and, in case the limit is reached, inform you of the storage limitation. Furthermore, we may process the information on your location, since your location is the determining factor when deciding the storage location for your data (e.g., if you are located within the European Union, you will be assigned the cloud in Europe).

We process certain information in order to manage your account and provide you Backup services under the contractual agreement with you.

_The legal basis to process this personal data as described under this Section, is performance of our contract with you (i.e., the EULA) and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._ 

##### C.1.7. Using add-ons  

If you use add-ons (e.g., the security services provided by Malwarebytes Inc., the mobile device management provided by Ivanti UK Ltd. or the asset management and discovery provided by Lansweeper NV) we may process certain license information, your name, email address username, IP address, your device information and similar in order to activate your license and respectively link it to your account.  

_The legal basis to process this personal data described under this Section, is performance of our contract with you (i.e., the EULA) and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._ 

##### C.1.8. Product improvement and technical support  

TeamViewer may process personal data to analyze server and device logs in order to identify vulnerabilities, crashes as well as other issues to consequently mitigate or fix them. During such analysis certain information that may include personal data is analyzed, such as the user information (e.g., email, IP address, status, language, organization), session ID, device ID, call or workflow data, license data, call ID, workflow information (ID, title, etc.), multimedia assets (e.g., type of the asset, ID, name etc.), information related to certain task (ID; name, comment, creation date etc.), or picking information (order ID, shelf location, status etc.). We are processing your personal data in connection with its product improvement activities in order to provide you with better and improved services, and, consequently, for the enhancement of the contract with you.

Please note that TeamViewer has put additional technical and organizational measures in place, e.g., pseudonymization as well as further strong technical and organizational measures to ensure security of the data. It is also important to note that we never access any content or connection data itself, but rather observe your interactions with our Software and Services.

For product improvement purposes, the overall usage patterns of TeamViewer Products are analyzed, e.g., information about how certain features of the Software and the Server Services are used, as well as the interactions. This may include the session metadata, feature usage (e.g., remote control, file transfer, settings, etc.), and how frequently they are being used. This information helps improve and further develop TeamViewer Products, e.g., to help decide whether certain functionalities of the Software shall be kept, amended, or improved, or whether to create new features or improve the design. Please note, that TeamViewer only assesses the interactions and at no point information or data that is being exchanged between you and your connection partner(s).

TeamViewer may analyze this data together with further information submitted to us, as further described under this Product Privacy Notice, as well as in our [General Privacy Notice](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/privacy-and-cookies/).

_The legal basis to process this personal data described under this Section, is performance of our contract with you (i.e., the EULA) and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._ 

##### C.1.9. Analyzing and fixing crashes in mobile applications  

TeamViewer may process your personal data to analyze crashes in mobile applications. This is done only if the customer enables the automatic log of crashes. In such case, all crash logs are sent to TeamViewer server where they are analyzed, and bug fixes are implemented. Such crash logs may contain information on relevant sessions (ID, security tokens, IP address, username device, etc.), as well as device information (ID, device name, IP address, application version, device logs) or user information (e.g., email, IP address, status, language, organization).

_The legal basis to process this personal data described under this Section, is performance of our contract with you (i.e., the EULA) and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._

#### C.2. Ensuring your security and that of others

The security of our customers, users and employees is extremely important for TeamViewer. To achieve these purposes, TeamViewer has implemented a number of processes and procedures, so that fraudulent or suspicious activities are identified, and TeamViewer may take appropriate action. These measures also serve the prevention of abuse and fraud by identifying abnormal or unexpected usage. To do so, we need to evaluate the usage of the Software in order to recognize abusive or abnormal patterns and thus to help protect our network and service integrity at any time. Doing so, we may process certain personal data, e.g., data associated with your remote connections, IP addresses, derived locations, various user interactions and patterns as well as device information (e.g., device IDs as well as TeamViewer IDs). These processes are intended primarily to achieve the above aim i.e., to protect stakeholders as well as TeamViewer’s interests.

Subject to the Product, our users and customers also have the possibility to partake in the connection risk scoring (beta feature), which provides alerts within the Software on the possibly suspicious behavior of your connection partners. For these purposes, the results of our risk analysis are being used.

We will share information about the connecting user’s account with the recipient to establish that the connection is trusted. The user account data may include displayed country, domain of e-mail address, license status, age of account, VPN usage, etc.

If you believe we have blocked you and your devices in error, please contact our [customer support](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/global/support/customer-support/) in order to unblock your access.

_The legal basis to process your personal data as described under this Section is, performance of our contract with you (i.e., the EULA) and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR, or our legitimate interest and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR._

#### C.3. Conducting license audits

We may analyze your use of the Software and/or Server Services for security purposes, as well as for license auditing. To that end, we may use, and implement technical measures regarding the functionality of the Software and the Server Services to assess whether your usage pattern is in line with the indicated usage volume and thus with the chosen license type, and to detect whether the contractually agreed scope of use is being exceeded by customers or users in individual cases.

_The legal basis to process your personal data as described under this Section, is performance of our contract with you (i.e., the EULA) and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._

#### Learn more

##### C.3.1. Free Version  

If you are using our so-called Free Version of the Software as defined in the [EULA](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/eula/), we may analyze your Product usage data in accordance with Sections A.1, B.1.1, B.2.2, as well as B.1.8 of our [EULA](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/eula/) to assess whether your usage pattern is in line with your indicated usage purpose and thus with the chosen license type. This assessment, which may also include an analysis of the domain of an email-address you have provided in the course of signing up for a TeamViewer account (see above Section C.1.1), will result in a so called “commercial score”. Depending on this score, we may determine that a fee-based license, as opposed to a Free Version, is required for your usage pattern of our Product, and we will inform you accordingly.

If you continue to use our Product in a way that indicates a violation of Section B.1.8 of the [EULA](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/eula/), we may limit or ultimately block your access to the Server Services and ask you to purchase a fee-based license. In certain cases, this may involve an automatic decision-making process, where TeamViewer systems are configured to automatically put in place a limitation or even a blocking of your use of the Product.

If you think you are using our Product within the scope of the Free Version license, you may submit a corresponding request by way of our online form, for which we ask you to submit your name, email-address, affected TeamViewer Device ID, and an explanation on your usage. TeamViewer will then analyze your submission and again evaluate your detected usage patterns. In the course of the evaluation process, we may also ask you to submit a declaration confirming your use of our Product for private, non-commercial purposes only. For this declaration, we may ask you to submit your name, postal address, explanation of your usage, and your signature.  

##### C.3.2. Paid license  

If you have purchased our paid license, we may from time to time monitor your use of our services for license audit purposes, especially, to check whether your use of the Software and its features is in line with your license scope. If we determine any discrepancies and especially, the overuse, we may notify you via in-product messaging and ask you to discontinue the overuse or alternatively, purchase additional licenses.

Please refer to Section B.1.4 of the [EULA](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/eula/) in this connection.

If you will not discontinue the overuse or purchase additional licenses, we may block your Server Services until the dispute is resolved or terminate the agreement with you.

We may also process certain personal data in connection with your payments. In case of the payment defaults, in addition to sending out payment reminders, we may block your Software and Server Services in accordance with our [EULA](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/eula/), as well as involve external debt collection agency.

#### C.4. Support and Feedback  

##### C.4.1. Processing your feedback  

When you provide feedback concerning your experience when using TeamViewer Products (e.g. through our [user focus program](https://ufp.teamviewer.com/landing), rating our products, or by reporting bugs or feature requests), we will collect and process your account ID (if you provide the feedback while logged-in), your country and language settings, as well as any information you submit in your inquiry  or rating (including attachments such as log files or screen shots), which may contain your email-address, your name, company information, phone number, license key, or your TeamViewer Device ID. You may also provide us with logs stored on your local device for analytical purposes. In such case we will only process your data for the purposes of resolving the issue.

In the User Focus Program, any information disclosed in a survey, interview or recording may be processed in connection with product improvement activities. This may contain your email address, your name, company information, phone number, license key, audio and/or video recordings and account ID.

_  
The legal basis to process your personal data as described under this Section, is performance of our contract with you (i.e., the EULA) and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR, our legitimate interest and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR or your consent as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR_

##### C.4.2. Providing technical support  

When you request technical support, we may collect and process your data for providing support, e.g., for IT fault analysis, troubleshooting and remote maintenance. We may also process server logs and logs from your device, as provided by you.

_The legal basis to process your personal data as outlined above under this Section is performance of our contract with you (i.e., the EULA) and thus as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._ 

##### C.4.3. Bug Bounty Program (selected Products)  

We embrace any responsible disclosure in order to make our Products and Services better. Therefore, we offer a clear guideline for ethical hackers by providing a [VDP](https://vdp.teamviewer.com/#/page/0/Index) (Vulnerability Disclosure Policy) for selected Products which are subject to our choice. Our aim is to challenge ourselves by allowing you to investigate and discover various bugs or vulnerabilities pertaining to security exploits of our software.

You may participate in the so-called bug bounty or similar program anonymously. However, if you decide to submit your personal data, we may process it in order to properly identify you (e.g., your name, last name, pseudonym) as well as your contact information (e.g., email-address, postal address, phone number), your credentials, your country of residence and other personal information, as submitted by you.

The purpose of the processing is to work with you in order to resolve the bug and any associated topics around it. As mentioned above, you may also participate within the Program anonymously.

_The legal basis of this processing is fulfillment of the participation terms and conditions, i.e., Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR._

#### C.5. Marketing

TeamViewer may contact and inform its customers and users through in-product messages (using your TeamViewer Device ID and, if you are a registered user, your email) about changes to or improvements of our Products, entirely new products, or to provide you with tips on how to best use our Products as well as other useful information (e.g., on discounts, freebies or giveaways).

In determining whether and how we contact our customers and users, we may also process the license type, language and version of the Product, and/or country, and we may also draw on data we have gathered through analyses measures as described in Section C.5 of this Privacy Notice as well as Section C.6. of [our General Privacy Notice](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/privacy-and-cookies/).

If you would like to opt-out from receiving such in-product messages, please follow the instructions in [our Community](https://community.teamviewer.com/English/discussion/comment/98469#Comment_98469). For opting out from our email communication, please use the unsubscribe button included in the emails.

_The legal basis to process your personal data as described under this Section is our legitimate interest and thus as described in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR on the basis of § 7 para. 3 of the German Unfair Competition Act (UWG), or in some cases your consent, as defined in Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR._

#### C.6. App-stores

Some of our apps can be downloaded in Google Play as well as on Apple App Store. The app-stores usually provide the app developers (in this case, TeamViewer), with statistics of the downloads including ratings of the relevant app. Please note, that these data are provided to TeamViewer within the app-store directly based on download and ratings of the users of our app, including you.

_The Legal basis for processing your personal data in this regard is our legitimate interest, i.e. as described in Art. 6 Sec. 1 lit. f) GDPR._

For more information on how your app-store process your personal data, please refer to their respective privacy policies:  

#### C.7. Processing within the scope of legal requirements

We may process your personal data to comply with applicable law or act upon valid legal proceedings, including inquiries from law enforcement or government agencies, to investigate or participate in civil discovery, litigation, or other adversarial legal proceedings.

_The legal basis to process your personal data as outlined within this Section is compliance with a legal obligation, and thus Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c), or our legitimate interest and thus Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR._

D. Recipients
-------------

Our employees, who administer, maintain and further develop TeamViewer’s website, Products and Services may receive access to your personal data. To that end, TeamViewer has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure to third parties and to ensure that only relevant individuals, who act within their job description and have a need-to-know interest in accessing any of your personal data, will have access to the data for which they have sufficient clearance.

In addition, we utilize services of external service providers (e.g., Microsoft, Amazon Web Services, Inxmail GmbH, Cloudfare etc.), as well as our affiliate network worldwide (e.g., TeamViewer entities in Greece, USA, Australia, Austria, Japan etc.). Furthermore, TeamViewer may transfer your personal data to third parties (e.g. Google, Microsoft) in order to ensure the security of its services, or the security of its customers.

All mentioned third-party providers and employees of such providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide.

TeamViewer chooses all third-party service providers with due care, obligates them to confidentiality, and concludes data processing agreements with them in accordance with the standards of the GDPR, as far as necessary. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

TeamViewer will generally not transfer your personal data outside the EU and/or EEA. However, there are some exceptions to this rule, which include data transfers for group internal services provided from outside the EU, including Australia, USA and Armenia as an example.

Whenever TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have a level of protection recognized as adequate by the EU, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. In particular, we will conclude model contracts with corresponding entities in accordance with applicable laws. Please refer to this [LINK](https://commission.europa.eu/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/standard-contractual-clauses-scc_en) to obtain further information on the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established outside the EU or EEA.

#### Learn more

* If you use our Product, contact us through the contact, support, and feedback features, and/or if you request a quote, TeamViewer employees that are responsible for the respective service will receive access to your personal data. Aside from TeamViewer employees, your personal data may be processed by employees of third-party services providers, who assist us in handling your requests, e.g., if you use our chat functionality on the website, speak to us on the phone (e.g., external call centers), or contact us through forms on certain website landing pages (e.g., employees of the website support suppliers).
* If you post a comment in TeamViewer’s community or blog, your comment content and name/username will be publicly available and may appear in search engines. Aside from TeamViewer employees, employees of the hosting company may receive access to your personal data as described in Section C.3.
* If you purchase a TeamViewer Product, TeamViewer employees concerned with processing such transactions will receive access to your data. We also use the services of third-party payment token providers, such as PPRO Latin America GmbH and Adyen N.V. respectively. In addition, our fraud prevention software may also process your data on our behalf.
* In connection with hosting and processing your data on your behalf, we may use certain Subprocessors, e.g., Anexia Internetdienstleistungs GmbH, Amazon Web Services, IBM Deutschland GmbH, Google Ireland Ltd. or TeamViewer Austria GmbH etc.
* TeamViewer may transfer your personal data to third parties if we offer participation in campaigns, contests, reservations, or contract agreements in conjunction with a third party. In this case, you will be specifically informed about the transmission to the third parties.
* For web analytics and (re-)marketing activities, we rely on a number of third-party providers, which will process personal data on our behalf as explained in more detail in [our Cookie Notice](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/#cookie-notice).
* Finally, TeamViewer uses external third-party service providers to help operate its business, such as providers of IT operation and maintenance services, (cloud) storage service providers and providers of (cloud) collaboration tools. Examples include Amazon Web Services, and Microsoft (Dynamics 365, Azure).

E. **Retention and deletion**
-----------------------------

TeamViewer retains your personal data for as long as is necessary according to the relevant legal basis for its processing. The exact retention period will thus depend on the categories of personal data and the processing purposes. In some cases, we are legally required to retain personal data for a certain period of time. Once this period has lapsed and a purpose for processing the data no longer exists, we will delete or anonymize the data in accordance with data protection obligations. The information about your TeamViewer account will be kept as long as your user relationship exists. In general, TeamViewer accounts are deleted after two years of account inactivity. Account inactivity means that you have not logged into your TeamViewer account with an active internet connection. Accounts are deemed active as long as they are connected or attached to a valid paid license. A deviating deletion term may apply, in particular due to regional requirements and/or security reasons.

F. Statutory/contractual requirement
------------------------------------

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to engage in a contractual relationship with us or receive adequate support from us.

G. Special processing cases
---------------------------

Please refer to Section C.6 of our General Privacy Notice in this regard.

H. Your Rights
--------------

You may contact us either in writing by email at [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or via [web form](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/trust-center/world-class-privacy/data-subject-request/) in order to exercise the following rights to the extent you are entitled to so under applicable law:

* You have the right to request information about the processing of your personal data in accordance with Art. 13 and 14 GDPR (Right to information);
* You may request access to your personal data as well as request a copy of your personal data (right of access, Art. 15 GDPR);
* You may request that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data (Right to rectification, Art. 16 GDPR and Right to erasure, Art. 17 GDPR); the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
* You may request that we restrict the processing of your personal data (Right to restriction of processing, Art. 18 GDPR);
* You may request to receive your personal data, which you provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and transmit it without hindrance or have it transmitted to another controller (Right to data portability, Art. 20 GDPR).
* **You may object, at any time, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to the processing of your personal data which is based on the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. The processing of your personal data will then be cancelled, unless we demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms or the processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims (Right to object, Art. 21 GDPR).**
* You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data.

The relevant supervisory authority for TeamViewer is _Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Lautenschlagerstraße 20, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany_.

Should you have any questions on the processing of your personal data by TeamViewer Germany GmbH in relation to your contractual relationship, please contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

I. Compliance with the CCPA
---------------------------

Pursuant to the California Consumer Privacy Act (“**CCPA**”), you will not receive discriminatory treatment for exercising your privacy rights. You may also designate an authorized agent to make a privacy request on your behalf.

J. Compliance with Brazilian LGPD
---------------------------------

TeamViewer has checked the compliance topic with the Brazilian Data Protection Law Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados Pessoais (Law No. 13,709/2018) (“**LGPD**“) to ensure that our measures and procedures under the GDPR cover the topics within the LGPD. The privacy notice under the LGPD is available for Brazilian visitors and users under [www.teamviewer.com/en-us/privacy-notice](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/#lgpd).

K. Changes to this Notice
-------------------------

TeamViewer may, from time to time, make amendments to this Privacy Notice to reflect the changes in our processing activities.

**Privacy Notice for Cookies**
------------------------------

_Version as of July 2022_

TeamViewer Germany GmbH and its affiliates take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, such as name, address, email-addresses, IP address, or user behavior etc. The following privacy notice (“**Cookie Notice**”) provides you with information about the processing of personal data in relation to our use of so-called “cookies”, pixels and similar technologies, (together, “**Cookies**”) on our websites, as well as their business purpose and how they allow us to improve our service and run our business. It also tells you how you can manage or delete the Cookies that are stored on your device or manage the use of Cookies.

A. Controller
-------------

TeamViewer Germany GmbH (“**TeamViewer**”), Bahnhofsplatz 2, 73033 Göppingen, Germany is controller pursuant to Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“**GDPR**”) concerning any processing of personal data for which we determine the purpose and means of processing. TeamViewer is responsible for the Cookies set on all of our websites.

The exception applies with regards to the sub-page [Investor Relations](https://ir.teamviewer.com/websites/teamviewer/English/1/investor-relations.html) (“**IR**”). For the cookies set on the IR sub-page, TeamViewer SE is the controller under the GDPR.

B. Data Protection Officer (DPO)
--------------------------------

TeamViewer appointed an external data protection officer (DPO). In addition, TeamViewer established a dedicated Privacy team, which closely collaborates with the DPO. The Privacy team as well as the DPO can be reached at [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or at TeamViewer Germany GmbH, for the confidential attention of the DPO, Bahnhofsplatz 2, 73033 Göppingen, Germany.

C. All about the Cookies
------------------------

#### C.1. What are the Cookies?

Cookies are small text files containing information related to your internet settings, which are downloaded by your browser to the device you use when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website (first-party Cookies) on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognizes that Cookie (third-party Cookies). Cookies perform a variety of useful jobs, such as remembering your preferences, adapting the content that you see and improving your online experience.

#### C.2. When and how does TeamViewer place Cookies?

TeamViewer uses Cookies on its websites (such as teamviewer.com, login.teamviewer.com, teamViewerIOT.com, and other TeamViewer sub-domains such as login.teamviewer.com, get.teamviewer.com, www.lifear.com) and applications. Any device with which you are visiting these websites will receive at least some Cookies from TeamViewer, depending on the consent that you give when first visiting our website or changing your Cookie preferences at a later stage.

When you visit our websites for the first time with a specific device, we will ask you to choose your preferences through our Cookie banner (“**Banner**”). Within the Banner you can make a choice according to your wishes, either allowing us to set certain or all Cookies by category, limiting the setting of the Cookies or not selecting any at all. Please note, however, that some Cookies will always be active, and we do not ask for your consent for these. This applies for “strictly necessary” Cookies, because – as their name suggests – we need to place them for the proper functioning of our website (see also Strictly Necessary Cookies section below).

_The legal basis for the collection and processing of personal data in this case is, therefore, your consent, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a), Art. 49 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR or our legitimate interest, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR respectively._

#### Learn more

If you are using the Free Version software as defined in our EULA and Product Specifications, we may place certain third-party Cookies (e.g., Google Analytics) on your device regardless of your preferences based on contract pursuant to Section B.2.2 of our EULA. As specified in our EULA, a key element of and part of the product specification for the Free Version software is the display and receipt of personalized marketing messages in the software as well as the processing of personal data necessary to provide such personalization. In this context, we set certain cookies which enables TeamViewer to analyze your product usage as well as your browsing behavior on our websites. In doing so, we may assess your product usage history (e.g., how long or how often have you been using TeamViewer), how you interacted with our in-product messages, how often have you visited our websites or which pages have you looked at. This information then will help us determine the offers that are, in our opinion, most relevant for you on our website, ads or through in-product-messages.

Otherwise, you can change your preferences at any time in our Cookie Settings.

#### C.3. What types of Cookies are being used?

There are different types of Cookies used web-wide, that differ from each other by the various criteria, aims as well as the purposes. TeamViewer, as many other companies in the world, utilizes different sets of Cookies depending on which purpose we are pursuing. TeamViewer uses i.e., functional and strictly necessary Cookies in order to make our websites function properly and to display contents in accordance with your location (e.g., language settings), and we also use marketing and retargeting Cookies, e.g., Google Ads or Google Analytics.

#### Learn more

#### Different types regarding the provider of the Cookie

TeamViewer uses both, first- and third-party Cookies. First party Cookies are those set by TeamViewer itself. All other Cookies are third party Cookies, from companies such as Google Analytics, Facebook, LinkedIn etc. In some cases, the information derived from these Cookies may allow us to associate information with an identifiable individual, i.e., personal data.

#### Different types regarding the duration of storage  

##### **Session Cookies** 

Session Cookies last only for the duration of your visit of our website and are deleted when you close your browser. These help us to identify that a user of a particular device is navigating from page to page, supporting website security or basic functionality. Many of the Cookies we use are session Cookies. For example, they help us to measure the average time you spend on our website.  

##### **Persistent Cookies** 

Persistent Cookies continue to exist even after you have closed your browser and allow a website to remember your actions and preferences, particularly remember you as an existing user. Sometimes persistent Cookies are used by websites to provide targeted advertising based upon the browsing history of the device. TeamViewer uses persistent Cookies in a few ways, for example to distinguish users of our website and/or our products.

#### Different types regarding the purpose of use

Both session as well as persistent Cookies can serve different purposes and may be placed either by TeamViewer or by a third party. We differentiate between _strictly necessary Cookies, performance Cookies, functional Cookies, and marketing and targeting Cookies._ 

##### **a) Strictly necessary Cookies** 

These Cookies are essential in order to enable us to provide you with basic and security features of our website. Without these Cookies, certain services you have asked for cannot be provided, such as the use of areas of our website that are restricted to registered users (a Cookie, which identifies registered users to recognize them throughout the visit and upon return, e.g., within the login area of our Management Console) and webshop related services. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in or filling in forms. These Cookies are not implemented to gather information about you for other purposes such as marketing or analytics.  

##### **b) Performance cookies** 

These Cookies are used to collect information about the performance of our website and your visit and use of our website, for example, the number of visitors that used our website and the pages that are popular among our visitors. These Cookies do not collect information that directly identifies a visitor, although they may collect the IP address of the device used to access the site. Such information is used for the purpose of improving our website and the general user experience. Without the performance Cookies we will not be able to improve our website and its functionalities to provide you with the best surfing experience. If you do not allow these Cookies, your visit to our site will not be counted, which will negatively impact us when trying to improve our website.  

##### **c) Functional Cookies** 

These Cookies allow TeamViewer’s website to remember your preferences, such as your username, language settings, and/or the region you are in. These Cookies help to provide enhanced, more personal features. They can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customize or provide services you have asked for such as watching a video, using the chat functionality or commenting on a blog. These Cookies do not track your browsing activity across other websites.  

##### **d) Marketing and Targeting Cookies** 

These Cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. These Cookies collect several pieces of information about your browsing habits. They are usually placed by advertising networks with our permission. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other organizations, such as media publishers. These organizations do this in order to provide you with targeted adverts more relevant to you and your interests. This type of advertising is called online behavioral advertising. Furthermore, these Cookies allow us to analyze your website browsing behavior and thus allows us to customize our product marketing approach, e.g., help us decide on whether, when, and how to inform or get in touch with you based on your interests.

D. Is personal data about you processed through Cookies?
--------------------------------------------------------

Not all Cookies collect and process personal data about you. Instead, anonymous data may be used in many cases. In certain instances, however, Cookies will help us and our partners to collect and process personal data. Below sections will tell you more about the applicable categories of personal data and the purposes of the collection and processing that occur in this context. In general, it can be said that the data serves to provide the best possible experience to you when you use our websites and products and to further business interests of TeamViewer.

Please note that you can stop such collection and processing of personal data the same way you can stop the use of Cookies in general (see more under the Cookie Settings).

#### D.1. Personal data processed through web analytics and (re-)marketing applications

TeamViewer uses various web analytic applications and (re-)marketing tools, social media plugins, as well as third party integrated services. By and through these applications and tools, personal data as set out in this Cookie Notice are collected and may be combined with other personal data, we may collect from you.  

##### **1\. Google Analytics and other analysis tools provided by Google** 

TeamViewer uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA / Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, 4 Barrow Street, Dublin, Ireland, or any other Affiliate of Google LLC (“**Google**“). When you visit our website for the first time and consent to our use of Cookies, you will be assigned a cookie with a unique user identification, i.e., a Google Analytics Client ID depending on your Cookie settings.

TeamViewer uses Google Analytics with the extension “anonymizeIp()”. Thereby, IP addresses are processed in a shortened form. The information generated by cookies about your use of this website is usually transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the USA. Only in exceptional circumstances will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of the Google Analytics data collection will not be merged with other data from Google.

_The legal basis to conduct and use the results of these analyses is your consent, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a), Art. 49 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR._

#### Learn more

Other tools TeamViewer uses in this context that are also provided by Google include:

* Google Tag Manager (a tag management system that allows TeamViewer to quickly and easily update tracking codes and related code fragments, collectively known as “tags” on our website or mobile app);
* Google Big Query (an enterprise data warehouse that enables SQL queries using the processing power of Google’s infrastructure; TeamViewer uses Big Query to store and query data sets which are collected by Google services such as Google Analytics, and the Big Query data is used to build flexible reports for evaluating our website performance);
* Google Display Network (used to measure the impact of unclicked Google Display Network ad impressions on the website, behavior of users, and conversions; please refer to https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/3105620 for further information); and
* Google Optimize (for A/B testing, offering to analyze user behavior by showing slightly varied website contents to different user groups, depending on profile matching; thereby, TeamViewer analyzes its online services, improves its web offerings, and can create an interesting user journey).

TeamViewer uses data gathered through your Google Analytics Client ID as well as other data generated from Google’s web analytics applications in order to perform analyses of your interactions with our products, services, and websites. With the help of Google’s Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, we will receive analyses on our users’ age, gender, and interest categories (please refer to https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en for further information).

Please visit the website https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en for an overview on Google’s approach on data protection for Google Analytics as well as their privacy policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en.

##### **2\. Security and identification** 

TeamViewer may use “Google reCAPTCHA” (hereinafter “reCAPTCHA”) on our websites. This service is provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”).

reCAPTCHA is used to check whether the data entered on our website (such as on a contact form or log-in area) has been entered by a human or by an automated program. To do this, reCAPTCHA analyzes the behavior of the website visitor based on various characteristics. This analysis starts automatically as soon as the website visitor enters the website. For the analysis, reCAPTCHA evaluates various information (e.g., IP address, how long the visitor has been on the website, or mouse movements made by the user). The data collected during the analysis will be forwarded to Google.

For more information about Google reCAPTCHA and Google’s privacy policy, please visit Google information pages linked [here](https://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/) and [here](https://www.google.com/recaptcha/intro/android.html).

_The legal basis for the data processing in this connection is the legitimate interest of TeamViewer, Art. 6 para. 1 f) GDPR, since we have a legitimate interest in protecting its site from abusive automated crawling and spam_.  

##### **3\. (Re-)Marketing/retargeting applications** 

##### **a) Google AdWords Conversion and Google Remarketing** 

TeamViewer uses Google AdWords in order to generate attention for our products and services by conducting targeted advertising campaigns on third-party websites and apps. Data generated by such campaigns helps us to determine the success rate of individual campaigns. We aim at providing you with advertisement that is of interest to you, to make its website more interesting, and calculate advertising expenses accurately.

_The legal basis for such processing of personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a), Art. 49 para 1 lit. a) GDPR, therefore, your consent._

#### Learn more

TeamViewer uses Ad Server Cookies, which scale certain parameters, such as display of ads or clicks by users. When you click on an ad delivered by Google that redirects you to our website, a cookie is stored on your computer by Google AdWords. These cookies usually expire within 30 days and are not supposed to be used to personally identify a user. In addition to these cookies, analytic values like a unique cookie ID, quantity of Ad impressions per storing, last impression and opt-out information (markings that the user does not want to be addressed any further) are usually stored. These cookies enable Google to recognize your internet browser.

If you visit certain pages on our website and provided the cookie stored on your device has not yet expired, we as well as Google are able to recognize that you clicked on an ad and were redirected to our website. Every Google AdWords customer receives a different cookie. Therefore, cookies cannot be tracked across different sites by TeamViewer, as is the case for all other AdWords customers. We merely receive statistical evaluations from Google. By and through these statistical evaluations, we can evaluate which advertisement campaign was particularly effective. Any additional data generated by the particular advertisement is not forwarded to TeamViewer; particularly, we cannot personally identify users through this information.

Through this (re-)marketing tool, your browser automatically connects to Google’s servers. Please note that scope and further use of the data processed by Google are subject to Google’s privacy policy and beyond TeamViewer’s control. We thus inform you based on our own knowledge:

By integrating AdWords, Google receives information that you visited a particular TeamViewer website or part thereof, and/or that you clicked on one of our advertisements. If you are registered with one of Google’s services, Google is able to match your visit to your Google account. Google may receive your IP address and/or may store it even if you are not registered with one of Google’s services and/or if you have not been logged in.

You may avoid tracking in various ways, e.g. through a setting of your browser software, particularly, by suppressing third party cookie installation in order to prevent receiving third-party ads; deactivating AdWords Cookies, by setting your browser so that cookies from www.googleadservices.com are being blocked; this can be done at https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous, however, such settings are deleted if you delete cookies; or permanently deactivating cookies in your browser under https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996.

Further information on Google’s approach to data privacy can be found under https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en. Alternatively, you can disable the use of cookies for interest-based advertising via the advertising network initiative, by following the instructions at http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/.

In addition to Google AdWords, TeamViewer uses the tool “Google Remarketing”. This is an application that allows us to address you again, even when you have left our website. After visiting our website and while you are surfing the internet, our advertisement can be displayed to you by and through this application. This is enabled by cookies stored on your device, which track and analyze user behavior on different websites for Google. Google can track your previous visits to our website.

According to its own statement, Google does not combine data gathered through Remarketing with any personal data Google may have stored about you. Furthermore, the data processed for these purposes is generally limited to pseudonymous information. If you do not want to be exposed to data processing through the Google Remarketing feature, you can disable it by changing the appropriate settings at https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous.

##### **b) Social media tracking tools, including “tracking pixels”** 

We may also use other tools on our website allowing us to offer you a more personalized and engaged web experience by offering you advertisements on your social media channels that are more relevant to you. To that end, we use cookie-based tools offered by the following third-party social media providers:

* **Facebook Inc.**, 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA; for further information on the implemented tool, please refer to https://developers.facebook.com/docs/facebook-pixel/implementation#base-code; additional information on data collection: https://www.facebook.com/help/186325668085084
* **LinkedIn Corporation**, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, California 94043, USA; for further information on the implemented tool and how to opt out of corresponding tracking, please refer to https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out; for further information on LinkedIn’s approach to privacy refer to: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=uno-reg-guest-home-privacy-policy
* **Twitter Inc.**, 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, California 94103, USA; for further information on the implemented tool and how to opt out of corresponding tracking, please refer to https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads; for further information on Twitter’s approach to privacy refer to: https://twitter.com/en/privacy.
* **Microsoft Corp.**, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA; for further information on the implemented tool and how to opt out, please refer to https://account.microsoft.com/privacy/ad-settings/signedout?lang=en-US; for further information on Microsoft’s approach to privacy refer to: https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement.

In each case, we integrate snippets of code provided by these social media operators that load a small library of functions (sometimes referred to as “tracking pixels”, i.e., transparent, pixel-sized images embedded in websites with a tracking functionality). These functions enable us to track your activities on our website, such as URLs visited, domains visited, device(s) used, and, in particular, advertising conversions (i.e., actions counted when you interact with one of our ads, such as clicking it and purchasing our product afterwards). They rely on cookies placed by the mentioned third-party providers, which may also enable us to match our website visitors to respective user accounts on the respective social media platforms.

_The legal basis for such processing of personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a), Art. 49 para 1 lit. a) GDPR, e.g., your consent. Please take note of your options to opt-out of such tracking and remarketing mentioned above._

E. Supplementary information
----------------------------

Not all Cookies collect and process personal data about you. Instead, anonymous data may be used in many cases. In certain instances, however, Cookies We may embed external content from third party websites (e.g., Facebook, YouTube) within our website periodically. In addition to this, we sometimes partner with third parties who provide services for us which you can navigate to from our website. These third parties may use Cookies, you can find out about their approach to Cookies on their websites.

**Privacy Notice of TeamViewer SE**
-----------------------------------

_Version as of April 2022_

### Introduction

We, TeamViewer SE, take protection of your personal data very seriously. The following notice provides an overview of how we ensure this protection and what kind of data is processed, and why. Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, for example your name, address, email addresses, number of shares, the information which intermediary bank you are using.

A. Controller
-------------

TeamViewer SE, Bahnhofsplatz 2, 73033 Göppingen, [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), is controller of your personal data pursuant to Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“**GDPR**”).

B. Data Protection Officer (DPO)
--------------------------------

TeamViewer SE appointed Ms. Katja Hauser as external data protection officer, who can be reached at [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), or at intersoft consulting services AG, DSB TeamViewer, Dürener Str. 189, 50931 Cologne.

C. Purpose of processing and respective legal basis
---------------------------------------------------

TeamViewer SE collects and processes different categories of personal data depending on the relevant purpose of the use, especially in connection with the management of investor and shareholder relations. The following sections outline the categories of data processed by us and respective purposes for such processing. If the legal basis for a processing is your consent, you may withdraw your consent at any time, such withdrawal however will not have any impact on the legitimacy of the processing itself prior to withdrawal of your consent.

### I. Management of investor relations

We may process your personal data collected at the events or roadshows, such as your name and contact information, as well as in connection with our Investor Relations News Alert (in case you have subscribed to it) or if you decide to get in touch with us via email or phone. Legal basis for the processing is your consent, Art. 6, para. 1 lit (a) GDPR or our legitimate interest, Art. 6, para. 1 lit (f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest is to answer your questions, provide information and maintain our investor relations.

### II. Processing of personal data of shareholders and their representative

We may process your personal data such as your name, contact information, your email address, your representative, your intermediary bank, number of shares in connection with you purchasing shares in TeamViewer SE. Such information is used to fulfil our legal obligations (e.g. inform the regulatory bodies if shareholders reach certain levels of share ownership) as well as organize annual shareholder meetings (“**Shareholder Meeting**”), including but not limited to preparing and sending out the invitations, issuing voting cards or respectively voting right tickets, compiling the list of participants and processing the power of attorneys. Legal basis for the processing is the legal obligation under stock corporation law to which we are a subject to, Art. 6, para. 1 lit (c) GDPR.

### III. Processing of personal data in connection with Shareholder Meetings

We may conduct our Shareholder Meetings either in person or without presence using the means of remote communication (“**virtual Shareholder Meeting**”) with the option of participating by an electronic connection.

In order to enable shareholders and their representatives to participate in the Shareholder Meeting (e.g. by checking their eligibility to participate) and to exercise their rights at the Shareholder Meeting (including granting and revoking powers of attorney and instructions) as well as to ensure a proper conduct of the Shareholder Meeting, the observance of voting bans, the lawful adoption of resolutions and evaluation of cast votes at the Shareholder Meeting, we may process the name, contact information, registration number, number of shares, voting behavior and results, submitted questions, statements (in writing or via video message), motions, counter-motions, nominations, instructions and objections of our shareholders and their representatives, and login information for our designated shareholder portal (shareholder/voting card number and password). Legal basis for the processing is the legal obligation under stock corporation law to which we are a subject to, Art. 6, para. 1 lit (c) GDPR.

The entire Shareholder Meeting may be broadcast live and publicly accessible on the Internet by means of video and audio transmission. If the Shareholder Meeting is conducted in person and you enter the recording area or make a verbal contribution during recording activities, this live broadcast will include your appearance and verbal contribution. The legal basis for this processing is Art. 6, para. 1 lit (f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest is to enable interested shareholders and the public to follow the Shareholder Meeting via the Internet in accordance with the express permission in the German Stock Corporation Act and our by-laws.

Insofar as we take down in shorthand your verbal contributions during the Shareholder Meeting without being legally obliged to do so, this is done to ensure the proper conduct of the Shareholder Meeting and to be able to deal with your questions and motions. The stenographic minutes will not be published. The legal basis for this processing is Art. 6, para. 1 lit (f) GDPR and our legitimate interest is to ensure that the Shareholder Meeting is executed properly and that our shareholders’ participation rights can be realized in the best possible way.

If you make use of the opportunity to submit questions, statements (in writing or via video message), motions, counter-motions, nominations or other requests that are dealt with or made available during or before the Shareholder Meeting, this will generally be done by stating your name, which other participants of the Shareholder Meeting may take note of. If we are not legally obliged to state your name in this context, the legal basis for the processing is Art. 6, para. 1 lit (f) GDPR and our legitimate interest is to inform the other shareholders of the name of the applicant.

### IV. Processing of personal data in connection with the shareholder portal

If we conduct the Shareholder Meeting virtually, the shareholders and their representatives will not be able to physically attend the meeting. They can, however, follow the entire meeting via video and audio transmission through the designated shareholder portal. In connection with the virtual Shareholder Meeting we will process your voting card number, log-in password, type of the power of attorney and personal data of your representative, as well as the instructions issued in connection with the Shareholder Meeting and any other information submitted by you in the shareholder portal. Legal basis for the processing is the legal obligation under stock corporation law to which we are a subject to, Art. 6, para. 1 lit (c) GDPR.

If we conduct a virtual Shareholder Meeting and provide the shareholder portal to enable you to conveniently manage your shareholder data, we will collect and process certain personal data on the web server log files, when you visit our shareholder portal in order to log in to attend the virtual Shareholder Meeting, manage your shareholder data or exercise your shareholder’s rights:

* Date and time of the request
* Notification whether the request was successful
* Requested URL
* Referrer URL (the previously visited page), if your browser sends this information
* Type of used web browser and operating system used
* IP address
* Port by which the access was made
* Actions performed within the portal
* Session ID and data
* Successful logins and logouts with the time stamp

Your browser automatically transfers this data to us when you visit our shareholder portal.

Legal basis for the processing is our legitimate interest, Art. 6, para. 1 lit (f) GDPR, since we have a legitimate interest in making the shareholder portal available to you and your representatives so that you can exercise your shareholder rights in a user-friendly manner and participate in the virtual Shareholder Meeting.

D. Cookies
----------

If we use cookies in the provision of the shareholder portal, we will only do so if this is necessary for the operation of the shareholder portal or if you have given your consent. In this case, when you visit the shareholder portal, we will inform you in a pop-up window about our cookies and associated data processing before using cookies and, if necessary, ask you for your voluntary consent.

E. Data Sources
---------------

If you are a shareholder, we receive your personal data either directly from you or from the custodian credit institutions or intermediaries who are involved in the deposit of shares you purchased.

If you act as representative of a shareholder, we receive your personal data from the shareholder who granted you the power of attorney and directly from you as far as your behavior during the Shareholder Meeting or your use of the shareholder portal is concerned.

F. Recipients
-------------

TeamViewer SE’s employees, who administer, maintain and manage our internal processes, will have access to your personal data. To that end, TeamViewer SE has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure to third parties and to ensure that only relevant individuals, who act within their job description and have a need-to-know interest in accessing any of your personal data, will have access to the data for which they have sufficient clearance.

Aside from TeamViewer SE’s employees, your personal data may be processed by employees of third-party services providers, who assist us in our daily business, such as providers of IT operation and maintenance services, (cloud) storage service providers and providers of (cloud) collaboration tools, as well as PR agencies. We use certain service providers in order to provide services typical for the capital market, such as EQS Group AG and Nasdaq Corporate Solutions International Ltd. for the management of investor relations as well as Link Market Services GmbH for the management of shareholder relations and Shareholder Meetings. Link Market Services GmbH also operates the shareholder portal used for organizing virtual Shareholder Meetings, exclusively on our behalf and in accordance with our instructions.

TeamViewer SE selects all third-party service providers with due care, obligates them to confidentiality, and concludes data processing agreements (DPAs) with them (including the providers listed above) in accordance with the standards of the GDPR, as applicable. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

In addition to above cases, your personal data may also be disclosed during or in connection with the Shareholder Meetings. If you, as a shareholder, make use of the opportunity to submit questions and your questions are dealt with during the Shareholder Meeting, this will generally be done by stating your name. The above applies likewise regarding the submission of statements (in writing or via video message), the publication of which will show your name and, in the case of a statement via video message, images of yourself. If you submit items for the agenda, motions, counter-motions or nominations that we have to make publicly available, e.g. on our company’s website, before the Shareholder Meeting pursuant to our obligations under stock corporation law, this will also generally be done by stating your name. Other participants of the Shareholder Meeting or even the public may take note of this. Furthermore, other shareholders, their representatives where applicable or other participants of the meeting can view the personal data contained in the participant list during the Shareholder Meeting and, if applicable, up to two years thereafter in accordance with Sec. 129 of the German Stock Corporation Act (AktG).

TeamViewer SE will generally not transfer your personal data outside the EU and/or EEA. However, there are some exceptions to this rule, which include data transfers for group internal IT services provided from outside the EU, including Australia, USA and Armenia. TeamViewer SE will otherwise transfer your personal data outside the EU and/or EEA only when required to do so by law or in case of orders from a competent authority. Currently we transfer personal data to our provider Nasdaq Corporate Solutions International Ltd. in the US. Legal basis for such transfer is a DPA with EU standard contractual clauses.

Whenever TeamViewer SE transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. In particular, we will conclude standard contractual clauses with corresponding entities and /. Please refer to [https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries\_en](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en) to obtain further information on the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established outside the EU or the EEA.

We will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction. We may be obliged to pass on your personal data to other recipients, such as when publishing voting rights notifications in accordance with the provisions of the German Securities Trading Act, or to authorities in order to comply with statutory notification obligations (e.g. to financial or criminal prosecution authorities).

G. Retention periods for personal data
--------------------------------------

Your personal data will be deleted once you withdraw consent, or once the purpose for processing has ceased to exist. In some cases, TeamViewer SE is legally obligated to retain data for a certain period of time. Your personal data will be deleted or anonymized as soon as they are no longer required for the purposes listed under Section C. and if the deleting or anonymizing does not conflict with legal requirements for proof and storage.

H. Statutory/contractual requirement
------------------------------------

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, by not providing your personal data, we may not be able to provide you with the relevant service or support, e.g. enable you to participate in our Shareholder Meeting or use all of the functionalities of our website; where we ask for consent and you choose not to provide it, or you block, disable or delete cookies, we may not be able to provide you with the information or service requested.

I. Your rights
--------------

You may contact us, e.g. under [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), in order to exercise the following rights to the extent you are entitled to under applicable law:

* You may request access to your personal data as well as request a copy of your personal data (right of access, Art. 15 GDPR);
* You may request that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data (Right to rectification, Art. 16 GDPR and Right to erasure, Art. 17 GDPR); the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
* You may request that we restrict the processing of your personal data (Right to restriction of processing, Art. 18 GDPR);
* You may request to receive your personal data, which you provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and transmit it without hindrance or have it transmitted to another controller (Right to data portability, Art. 20 GDPR);
* **You may object, at any time, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to the processing of your personal data which is based on the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. The processing of your personal data will then be cancelled, unless we demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms or the processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims (Right to object, Art. 21 GDPR).**

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data. In order to lodge a complaint, please contact the supervisory authority competent for your place of residency or alternatively, you may contact “Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Lautenschlagerstraße 20, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany“.

Should you have any questions, please contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

J. Changes to this Notice
-------------------------

TeamViewer may, from time to time, make amendments to this notice to reflect the changes in our processing activities.

### **PRIVACY STATEMENT – BRAZIL**

_Version as of March 2024_

This Privacy Annex for users located in Brazil supplements the information contained in the [TeamViewer Privacy Policies](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/) located at www.teamviewer.com/en-us/privacy-policy and applies solely to visitors, users and others who reside in Brazil (“consumers” or “you”). We adopt this annex to comply with the Brazilian Data Protection Law Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados Pessoais (Law No. 13,709/2018) (“LGPD”). Any terms defined in the LGPD have the same meaning when used in this annex.

### **LGPD**

On September 18, 2020, the Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados Pessoais (“LGPD”) came into effect for Brazilian residents. In addition to the rights outlined in our Privacy Policies, as a user located in Brazil, you may be able to exercise the following rights with respect to your personal information that we have collected, subject to certain limitations:

* **The right to confirmation of the existence of the processing.** You have the right to ask that we confirm whether we process your personal data.
* **The right to access the data.** You have the right to access the personal data we hold about you and certain information about how we use it and who we share it with, including information about any public and private entities we have shared your personal data with.
* **The right to correct incomplete, inaccurate or out-of-date data.** If you want to correct or revise any of the data we retain on you, you may do so by accessing your account and the information contained within it.
* **The right to anonymize, block, or delete unnecessary or excessive data or data that is not being processed in compliance with the LGPD.** Please note that, depending on the request, this may result in a suspension or discontinuation of certain services and may be governed by legal and/or contractual retention guidelines.
* **The right to the portability of data to another service or product provider, by means of an express request.** We provide you with the ability to move any of your account data to a third party, at any time.
* **The right to delete personal data processed with the consent of the data subject.** You have a right to request the permanent deletion of your data, subject to certain exceptions. However, please note that exercising this right may result in a suspension or discontinuation of services and may also be governed by legal and/or contractual retention guidelines.
* **The right to information about the possibility of not giving consent and about the consequences of the refusal.** You have the right to ask us to provide information about the possibility of not giving consent for the processing of your personal data and the consequences of such refusal.
* **The right to revoke consent.**

**Please note that not all of these rights listed above are absolute, and limitations/exceptions apply in some cases. For example, we may not be able to fully comply with your request if we are bound by certain legal restrictions or contractual requirements, but in those circumstances, we will still respond to notify you of such a decision.**

**_Exercising Data Portability and Deletion Rights_**  
To exercise the data portability and deletion rights described above, please submit a verifiable consumer request to us by contacting us under [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), at 1-800-638-0253, or [submitting a ticket](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/global/support/customer-support/) on our website.

We will need to verify your identity before processing your request. The verifiable consumer request must:

* We will need to verify your identity before processing your request. The verifiable consumer request must:
* Provide sufficient information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we collected personal information or a legal representative.
* Describe your request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate and respond to it.

We cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal information if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm the personal information relates to you. Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. We will only use personal information provided in a verifiable consumer request to verify the requestor’s identity or authority to make the request.

**_Response Timing and Format_**  
We endeavor to respond to a verifiable consumer request within thirty (30) days. The response we provide may explain the reasons we cannot comply with a request, if applicable. For data portability requests, we will select a format to provide your personal information that is readily useable and should allow you to transmit the information from one entity to another entity without hindrance.

### Payment Processor Terms

For orders placed in Brazil, PPRO Payment Services (“PPRO”) may provide you with payment processing services. In such cases, once the registration on the TeamViewer website is completed, the user will be able to choose among the local payment methods that PPRO makes available. The user acknowledges and declares that, before making the purchase, they knew of and had access to the information about the goods and services offered, in addition to the specific conditions related to the user's rights, according to the payment instrument used at the time of purchase fully and unlimitedly exempting PPRO from any liability in relation to the purchase carried out on the TeamViewer website. The user also declares they are aware and agrees to only provide correct and truthful information when making the purchase, fully and unlimitedly exempting PPRO from any responsibility for the data provided.

### **Changes to Our Privacy Annex**

We reserve the right to amend this privacy annex at our discretion and at any time.

### **Contact Information**

If you have any questions or comments about this annex, our Privacy Policies, the ways in which we collect and use your personal information, your choices and rights regarding such use, or wish to exercise your rights under Brazilian law, you may contact us at:

TeamViewer  
Attn: LGPD Data Processing Officer Committee  
5741 Rio Vista Drive  
Clearwater, FL 33760  
United States of America  
[\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)  
1-800-638-0253

Data Protection Information Sheet for TeamViewer Customers
----------------------------------------------------------

_Version as of July 17th, 2023_

This Data Protection Information Sheet provides an overview of how TeamViewer Germany GmbH, Bahnhofsplatz 2, 73033 Göppingen, Germany (hereinafter “TeamViewer” or “we”) collects and processes personal data of its customers.

1. **Processing as Processor.** When you use TeamViewer software and services as a customer (hereinafter “Customer” or “you”) and you are not a natural person, using the software or services in a purely personal or family activity (cf. Art. 2(2)(c) EU General Data Protection Regulation, “GDPR”), TeamViewer processes personal data in the meaning of Art. 4 GDPR and acts as Processor, whereas you act as Controller (Art. 28 GDPR). In the following, in addition to our [TeamViewer DPA](https://www.teamviewer.com/eula/#dpa)  and related [annexes](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/dpa-annex/) , as amended from time to time, we summarize what personal data we collect, process or use and what rights data subjects are entitled to in connection with the use of our software and services.
2. **Processing as Controller.** In addition, we process personal data as “controller” under the GDPR when providing our software and services. Information on such processing activities in accordance with Art. 13, 14 GDPR can be found in our [Privacy Notice for TeamViewer Products](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/#products).
3. **Information on data processing.** In connection with the use of TeamViewer software and services, we perform the processing activities described in [Annex 1](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/dpa-annex/) to our DPA, as amended from time to time. In connection with these processing activities, we use subcontractors, as set forth in [Annex 3](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/dpa-annex/) to our DPA, as amended from time to time.
4. **Technical and organizational measures.** When processing personal data, TeamViewer complies with Art. 32 GDPR and implements appropriate technical and organizational measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to the risk, taking into account the state of the art, the costs of implementation and the nature, scope, context and purposes of the processing as well as the risk of varying likelihood and severity for the rights and freedoms of natural persons. The measures adopted are specified in TeamViewer’s overview of technical and organizational measures (TOMs, [Annex 2](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/dpa-annex/) to our DPA), as amen-ded from time to time.
5. **Security of processing.** Taking into account the type of processing and the personal data available to TeamViewer, TeamViewer supports the Customer with appropriate technical and organizational measures to comply with Art. 32 – 36 GDPR, in particular with regard to the security of processing, notification of a personal data breach to the supervisory authority, communication of a personal data breach to the data subject, data protection impact assessments as well as the consultation with supervisory authorities.
6. **Data protection by design and by default.** Information on how TeamViewer protects personal data by design and by default can be found in TeamViewer’s overview of technical and organizational measures (Section 6 in our TOMs, [Annex 2](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/dpa-annex/) to the DPA).
7. **Assistance to the Customer in the execution of requests of data subjects.** TeamViewer assists the Customer with appropriate technical and organizational measures in the execution of requests to exercise the rights of data subjects. If a data subject contacts us directly to exercise his or her rights pursuant to Art. 12 et. seq. GDPR, we will immediately forward this request to the Customer.
8. **Rights of data subjects towards TeamViewer.** Under the conditions set forth therein, the GDPR grants data subjects the following rights, which the data subject may exercise towards TeamViewer as described in the [Privacy Notice for TeamViewer Products](https://www.teamviewer.com/privacy/#products):
    
    * Right of access (Art. 15 GDPR);
    * Right to rectification (Art. 16 GDPR);
    * Right to erasure (Art. 17 GDPR);
    * Right to restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR);
    * Right to data portability (Art. 20 GDPR);
    * Right to object (Art. 21 GDPR).
    
    In addition, we inform data subjects in accordance with Art. 13 and 14 GDPR when we obtain personal data from them or from another source.
    
    Data subjects may assert their rights by e-mail to [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), via a support ticket or in writing to TeamViewer Germany GmbH, Bahnhofsplatz 2, 73033 Göppingen, Germany.
    
9. **Data protection officer.** TeamViewer has appointed an external data protection officer who can be contacted at [\[email protected\]](https://www.teamviewer.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). You are also free to contact the relevant data protection authority, Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit Baden-Württemberg, Lautenschlagerstraße 20, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany.
10. **Further Information on security measures and certificates.** Further information on security and data protection measures and our certificates of TeamViewer and its partners (e.g., ISO 9001, SOC2, SOC3, HIPPA/HITECH and ISO 27001) can be found in the TeamViewer [Trust Center](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/trust-center/).

Please choose your region
-------------------------

Selecting a region changes the language and/or content on teamviewer.com

* * *

### SUGGESTED REGION

* ### Americas
    
    * [
        
        Americas - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/ams/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        América Latina - Español](https://www.teamviewer.com/latam/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    
    * [
        
        Brasil - Português](https://www.teamviewer.com/pt-br/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Canada - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-ca/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Canada - Français](https://www.teamviewer.com/fr-ca/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        United States - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-us/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
* ### Asia Pacific
    
    * [
        
        Asia Pacific - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/apac/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    
    * [
        
        Australia - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-au/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        中国 - 中⽂（简体）](https://www.teamviewer.cn/cn/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        香港 - 繁體中文](https://www.teamviewer.com/hk/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        India - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-in/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        日本 - ⽇本語](https://www.teamviewer.com/ja/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        New Zealand - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-nz/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        대한민국 - 한국어](https://www.teamviewer.com/ko/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        台灣-繁體中文](https://www.teamviewer.com/tw/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        ประเทศไทย - ภาษาไทย](https://www.teamviewer.com/th/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Việt Nam - Tiếng Việt](https://www.teamviewer.com/vi/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
* ### Commonwealth of Independent States
    
    * [
        
        CIS - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-cis/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        СНГ - Русский](https://www.teamviewer.com/ru-cis/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
* ### Europe
    
    * [
        
        Europe - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    
    * [
        
        Belgique - Français](https://www.teamviewer.com/fr/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        België - Nederlands](https://www.teamviewer.com/nl/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Bulgaria - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Croatia - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Cyprus - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Czechia - Čeština](https://www.teamviewer.com/cs/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Denmark - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Deutschland - Deutsch](https://www.teamviewer.com/de/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        España - Español](https://www.teamviewer.com/es/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Estonia - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Finland - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        France - Français](https://www.teamviewer.com/fr/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Greece - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Ireland - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Italia - Italiano](https://www.teamviewer.com/it/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Latvia - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Liechtenstein - Deutsch](https://www.teamviewer.com/de/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Liechtenstein - Français](https://www.teamviewer.com/fr/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Liechtenstein - Italiano](https://www.teamviewer.com/it/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Lithuania - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Luxembourg - Français](https://www.teamviewer.com/fr/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Magyarország - Magyar](https://www.teamviewer.com/hu/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Malta - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Nederland - Nederlands](https://www.teamviewer.com/nl/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Norway - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Österreich - Deutsch](https://www.teamviewer.com/de/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Polska - Polski](https://www.teamviewer.com/pl/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Portugal - Português](https://www.teamviewer.com/pt/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Romania - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Schweiz - Deutsch](https://www.teamviewer.com/de/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Suisse - Français](https://www.teamviewer.com/fr/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Svizzera - Italiano](https://www.teamviewer.com/it/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Slovakia - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Slovenia - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Sweden - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Türkiye - Türkçe](https://www.teamviewer.com/tr/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        United Kingdom - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
* ### Middle East Africa
    
    * [
        
        Middle East Africa - English](https://www.teamviewer.com/en-mea/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)
    * [
        
        Middle East Africa - Français](https://www.teamviewer.com/fr-mea/legal/privacy-and-cookies/?language-switched=true)

Change Region

* Products
* Solutions
* Resources
* Support
* Company
* Additional Links
